蒙太奇字幕组 (MontageSubs)
用爱发电 ♥ Powered by love
（华纳兄弟影业）
（奥泰梅萨移民拘留中心）
（美国-墨西哥边境）
Welcome.
欢迎
Our best guess, there's about 250, 275 people in there.
里面估计有250到275人
It's hard to count.
很难数清 可能比这还多
We need to be prepared for, like,
等正式行动的时候
300 people by the time we get there, right?
我们要做好带走300人的准备
Our cargo container, 18-wheeler,
我们这辆集装箱大卡车
That thing only holds 160 people.
拖一个集装箱 最多能装160人
I'm talking 'bout crammed in there tight...
还得是人挤人...
That's cheek to jowl.
前胸贴后背
...smashed face to face.
...脸贴脸的
Women and children first.
让女人孩子先上车
Listen, whoever's not on with us,
听着 那些上不了车的
They just run, on foot.
就让他们自己跑
That's it. If they're not with us, they run.
上不了车的 只能自己跑
Via de la Amistad, that's our exit route.
记住 我们从友谊路撤退
Runs east-west. It's about one mile from 905.
它是东西向的 离905公路约一两公里
Right.
好的
What you draggin' in that wagon?
你的小车里拉了什么？
Listen, I got HMEs.
有自制炸药
I got mortars, I got tear gas,
有发射筒 还有催泪瓦斯
I got whatever you guys need,
你们需要的我都有
But I'm a little unclear as to what the plan is.
可我还不清楚计划是什么
I'm gonna need some direction.
能不能说明一下？
Don't be unclear. I got a plan for us.
没什么不清楚的 我都计划好了
Well, what is it?
什么计划？
I mean, you want me to create a diversion?
要我来引开注意力吗？
You want me to blow something up? What do you want?
还是要炸掉什么 你说说
I want you to create a show, Pat. Okay?
我想让你策划一个隆重出场 帕特 好吗？
This is the announcement of the motherfuckin' revolution.
向所有人宣告革命开始了
Yeah.
好
Make it good. Make it bright. Impress me.
要盛大 要精彩 别让我失望
Team Two's entrance. We got that?
第二小队从这儿走 明白了吗？
Yep. That runs north and south.
对 那条路是南北向的
Perfect, perfect, perfect.
很好 很好
- Give Pat a walkie. - Gimme a walkie.
- 给帕特拿个对讲机 - 把对讲机给我
Big truck coming up Enrico Fermi...
听好 大卡车走费米路直接开到营房去
Channel five.
频道五
Copy that.
明白
- Yeah! It's game time. No more talking 'bout this. - Let's go!
- 好 讨论结束 行动开始 - 出发
- All right, let's go, let's go. - Let's fuckin' go.
- 好 我们走 - 赶紧出发吧
【特朗普墙：背景图像为特朗普首任期修建的美墨边境墙 象征美国边境治理策略的显著加强】
Watch, watch, watch.
都当心点儿
Get on your knees, like you 'bout to suck a dick.
跪下 跪舔姿势
Gate guard secure.
门卫搞定了
Hey, you. Get up. Hands up. Get up.
起床 举起手 起来
- Down. Hey you, get up. - Get your hands up.
- 趴下 起床 - 举起手来
- Wake up. All the way up! - Down on the ground.
- 起来 都给我起床 - 趴在那里
Hands up. Don't look at me.
举上去 别瞎看
- All the way up. - Wake up.
- 全给我起床 - 起来
Wake up, soldier boy.
起来 大兵
You died and went to pussy heaven, motherfucker.
你死了 进了老娘的生死簿
Put your arms to the side so I can see you.
把手从脸上拿开 给你验明正身
（西班牙语）醒醒 起床了 都醒醒
（西班牙语）醒一醒 都起来
（西班牙语）卡车在门口 该走了 都起来
（西班牙语）快点儿
（西班牙语）都醒醒
What's your name, dickhead?
报上名来 野鬼
I'm Captain Steven J. Lockjaw.
我是史蒂文·勒喉乔上尉
【勒喉乔：暗指以暴力噤声的铁腕人物】
My name is Perfidia Beverly Hills, and this is a declaration of war.
我叫叛娅·富山 我正式向你们宣战
【叛娅·富山：字面指对富人背叛及反抗】
We're here to right your wrongs, motherfucker.
我们是来纠正你们犯下的错误的
You got an army growin' in your fuckin' guts, and you put it there.
是你们亲手培育了反抗军 这是你自找的
You didn't count on me.
你想不到我会来
Oh, my God.
真不错
You didn't count on my fight.
你想不到我会反抗
The message is clear. Free borders, free bodies,
我们的主张很明确 边境自由 身体自由
【边境与身体自由：主张跨境流动与身体自主权】
free choices, and free from fuckin' fear!
选择自由 免于恐惧
【选择自由与免于恐惧：主张个人决定权与免于胁迫】
Sweet thing.
小美人儿
Is this funny?
没听懂吗？
Get up.
起来
Not on your feet.
没说你脚
Oh, not on your fuckin' feet.
我可没让你站起来
Since we playin'...
既然你想玩
get it up.
那就硬起来
Up.
快点儿
Yeah. Get it up.
对 硬起来
Guys, hurry up!
大家快走
Be careful!
当心 当心
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
动作都快点儿
Apurarse.
别磨蹭
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
快 快 快
But be careful! Be careful!
但要有序 注意脚下
All the way to the back.
都往里面走
Holy shit.
真见鬼
Keep it moving now.
不要停下
Up.
起来
Good boy.
真乖
You like lockin' people up, huh?
你喜欢把别人关起来 是吗？
Oh, yeah.
没错
Get on your fuckin' knees!
给我跪下
Now.
马上
Let's go, let's go.
快点儿跪下
Put it on.
戴上这个
Let's go!
别磨蹭
（外勤行动 边境战术应对小组）
Now get the fuck up.
现在你可以站起来了
Let's go. Hands up. Keep that dick up.
把手举起来 继续硬着
- All right. - Keep it up.
- 好吧 - 举过头
The fuck out.
往外走
Pat.
帕特
Go for Pat.
帕特在
Snap, crackle, pop, baby.
执行“霹雳”计划
Copy that.
收到
Come on, come on!
点起来 点起来
I declare war, motherfucker.
我们宣战了 下地狱吧
（西班牙语）还瞪我 你跑不了了
（西班牙语）懂吗？
（西班牙语）你们这群混蛋
（西班牙语）你这条恶心的蛆
（西班牙语）当心我把你剁成肉酱
I'll be seeing you very soon.
我们很快会再见面的
Not if I see you first, fuck face.
但是最好别让我先找到你
We are a political organization
我们是政治组织 是革命队伍
that is free from the eyes, the ears,
不怕监视 不怕偷听
and most importantly,
最重要的是
the weapons of the imperialist state, and this fascist regime!
我们不怕帝国主义和法西斯政权的大炮
You are a political prisoner of the French 75, motherfuckers!
你们现在是法式七五组织的政治犯
【法式七五：借用法国革命意象 亦为野战炮与酒名】
You've been captured by the French 75!
由法式七五组织执行关押
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
Fuck the police!
条子去死吧
【美国警察：常被指控滥权 系统性歧视 及过度使用武力】
（西班牙语）革命万岁
Let's go!
走吧
（西班牙语）下地狱去吧 一群吃人的恶鬼
Motherfuckers!
一群畜生
（西班牙语）我们走
（西班牙语）听着 冷静点儿
- Hold on, y'all, hold on. - Shit. Oh, shit.
- 别激动 都冷静一下 - 天啊
（西班牙语）真刺激
Where you get all this energy from?
你怎么开心的跟过年一样？
What are you talkin' about?
你说什么？
I'm getting Ghetto Pat tonight. I think I like you.
今晚穷鬼帕特是我的了
【穷鬼帕特：人物代号 原指贫民区或其居民】
You like Black girls?
你喜欢黑人女孩吗？
Yeah?
喜欢吗？
Do I like what?
我喜欢什么？
You like...
你喜欢
Y'all think he like Black girls? Y'all think he like me?
你们觉得呢？他喜欢我吗？
- I think he does. - 'Course I fuckin' like Black girls!
- 我看他喜欢你 - 我当然喜欢黑人女孩
So shoot this shit up!
把子弹都打光
- Let's go! - What the fuck do you think I'm doing here?
- 使劲射 - 不然我怎么会在这里
- Fuck your mother! - You know I like fuckin' Black girls!
- 打破不公 - 我最喜欢黑人女孩了
You know I like Black girls.
你知道我喜欢
And I love you. You love me? Tell me you love me.
对我说出来 说你爱我
- I love you. - Tell me you fuckin' love me.
- 我爱你 - 告诉我你爱我
Calm down. Calm the fuck down.
别急 要慢慢来
What I'm doing here is I'm creating a closed circuit
我现在 要做一个闭合的电路
to remove any static electricity.
这样就能消除外部的静电
And that right there...
这个东西
That's a shunt. You see that?
叫分流器 看到了吗？
Yeah.
看到了
This is your blasting cap.
这就是起爆用的雷管
Right here.
就是这东西
（百威啤酒）
Very important to keep your cap shunted like this
你去法院的时候 一定要把电路接好
when you enter the courthouse. You got that?
避免意外引爆 记住了吗？
Here's your main charge. This is your cell phone.
这个是炸药 这个是你的手机
Don't stop. I see the cell phone.
说下去 用手机做什么？
First thing you're gonna do is you're gonna turn on your cell phone...
第一步 先打开手机
without your...
不过千万 千万不能
without your cap attached...
不能先把雷管接上
so you don't accidentally detonate your charge.
否则有可能意外引爆
You're gonna wanna...
你还要记得...
You're gonna wanna put your hands here, right?
还要记得手放在这里 对吧
And then you wanna take your hands and the cap
然后用手握住你的雷管
and throw it in the circle.
放入目标地点
Senator Wilson, this is a warning for you.
威尔逊参议员 这是对你的警告
（公共电话）
We planted a bomb at the Haymarket office
我们在你连任竞选的办公室里
of your re-election campaign.
放了一个炸弹
We warned you, that abortion ban,
我们警告过你不要通告堕胎禁令
【堕胎权：女性自主决定是否终止妊娠的权利】
and you didn't wanna fuckin' listen.
可你根本不听
So, for my sisters in need, we will strike.
所以 为了受苦的姐妹们 我们要行动
【美国堕胎权：美国曾由宪法保障堕胎权】
【美国堕胎权：但该保障已被最高法院保守派推翻】
Sincerely yours,
大礼敬上
Perfidia Beverly Hills, motherfucker.
署名是叛娅·富山
【美国堕胎权：保守的州纷纷立法限制女性堕胎】
Revolutionary violence is the only way.
暴力革命是唯一的出路
No more tellin' me to vote.
投票是扯淡
No more tellin' me to overcome.
忍无可忍
"Nobody move, nobody get hurt" shit, it doesn't matter.
就算警察拿枪指着我的头 我也无所谓
Everybody pays.
人人都要付出代价
Don't even bother lookin' for the French 75.
不用费劲找法式七五
We'll find you.
我们会找你的
（西进银行）
- Okay, baby, you ready? - Yeah.
- 亲爱的 准备好了吗？ - 好了
All right.
弄好了
All right. Let's go.
准备就绪 我们走
- Babe... - Yeah?
- 亲爱的 - 怎么了？
Let's fuck while the bomb go off.
我想在爆炸的时候上你
No, babe.
不行
- Come on, baby. Let's fuck, baby. - Come on, baby, we gotta go.
- 来吧 我很饥渴 - 走吧 我们得快走
- Hurry. - Come on. Come on, baby.
- 快走 - 来吧 宝贝
- Let's fuck, baby. - No, baby. We gotta go.
- 就在这里 - 不行 我们得赶紧走
Come on. Come on.
快走
Come on, baby.
快来吧 宝贝
快走吧 宝贝
Hold on. Wait.
来看着我 别急
Bomb goes off in two minutes.
还有两分钟就要爆炸了
（联信银行）
Get down.
趴下
Bring 'em all!
我们走 把他们带走
Come on!
快点儿 都快走
Don't say a fuckin' word, okay?
别出声 懂了吗？
You understand me?
听懂没有？
Get the rest!
都拿上
Oh, yeah.
对了
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
我们走 快走
Come on, come on!
都快一点儿 快走快走
Stay right there. Don't you fuckin' move.
不许动
Grab him! Let's go.
抓住他 我们走
Stay right fucking there, okay?
一步也别动 听到了吗？
You fucking move, I'll blow your fucking head off.
要是敢动 就让你脑袋开花
Regular-working White girl.
一看就是个女白领
Now do your thing.
去大显身手吧
《一　　　》
《一战　　》
《一战再　》
《一战再战》
We have two devices for two locations,
我们准备了两套遥控器 爆破两个地点
set three blocks apart.
之间相隔三个街区
Mae West completes her device in the administration building,
梅·韦斯特负责安装行政大楼的炸弹
【梅·韦斯特：借用好莱坞性感女星之名 暗指利用种族与外表特权作为渗透工具】
Perfidia and I take the courthouse.
我和叛娅负责法院的遥控器安装
Bombs are planted,
炸弹已提前放好
devices are detonated by remote at 7 p.m. after hours.
遥控装好后 晚上七点下班后远程引爆
From here on in,
从那一刻开始
it's one battle after another.
就要一战再战
【译注：白人已过安检 黑人则面临额外搜身】
（禁止吸烟）
What do you want me to do?
你想让我做什么？
I want you to do your worst.
让你为我做最坏的事
You can blow up anything you want,
你想炸掉什么都可以
it doesn't make any difference to me.
我根本不在乎
I want my hat. And my gun.
我要我的帽子 还有我的枪
If you wanna keep doing what you're doing,
要是你不想被人告发
You'll meet me at the Primrose Path, 2300.
那就今晚11点 到春歧途酒店找我
♪ Soldier boy ♪
♪ 小战士
♪ Oh, my little soldier boy ♪
♪ 哦 我的小战士
♪ I'll be true to you ♪
♪ 我会对你忠诚 ♪
♪ You were my first love ♪
♪ 你是我的初恋
♪ And you'll be my last love ♪
♪ 也是我最后的爱人 ♪
Can we go slowly? Wanna take my shoes off.
能不能慢慢来？我想把鞋脱了
♪ I will never make you blue ♪
♪ 我永远不会让你伤心 ♪
Shut...
闭起...
...up.
...嘴来
♪ I'll be true to you ♪
♪ 我会对你忠诚 ♪
♪ In the whole world ♪
♪ 在这个世界上
You're gonna let me go, right?
我进出自由 对吧？
♪ You can love but one girl ♪
♪ 你只能爱一个女孩
Yes, ma'am!
是 长官
♪ Let me be the one girl ♪
♪ 让我做那个女孩吧
♪ For I'll be true to you ♪
♪ 因为我会对你忠诚 ♪
Holy shit!
太帅了
Bitch, I felt like Tony Montana!
看到了吗？姐是疤面煞星
【《疤面煞星》（1983）：指像主角东尼·蒙大拿那样的权力与野心】
Yeah!
没错
Fuck!
看看
Yes!
厉害
It's cathartic.
打得太爽了
This pussy right here...
你说姐这个逼...
That one?
你说下面那个？
What's it for?
干什么用的？
- War! Bitch. - Um... Fun!
- 打仗 - 快活
Nah.
不对 错了
The pussy ain't for fun.
这不是用来快活的
This is the fun. The guns is the fuckin' fun.
你看这个 开枪才叫快活
Pussy is the fucking weapon.
咱们的身体就是武器
I mean...
你看
I see it.
我知道
A White-bred,
那一套白人中产
philistine, asshole corporate culture,
市侩庸俗 恶心透顶的公司文化
whose only end
它唯一的目的
is to perfect the science of advertising.
就是打更多广告 捞更多钱
But I ain't gonna hold ya, bitch.
我跟你说实话
If he treats me different after I drop
他要是敢对我不好
this motherfucker thing inside my stomach, bitch,
等这个小东西从我肚子里爬出来
we gonna have a fuckin' problem. Kill him, too.
我可不忍着 你看我宰了他
Bae, stop.
宝贝 别这样
I'll kill him dead!
看我敢不敢
Before he beats me!
趁他还没打倒我
What the fuck? That...
说什么呢 姐们儿？
It's like she doesn't even realize she's pregnant.
她好像不知道自己怀孕了一样
Some other white chocolate daddy over there and all this shit.
那就是孩子爸爸 长得跟其他白巧克力一样
【白巧克力爹：俚语 黑人妻子讥讽性称呼白人丈夫】
You right.
说得对
You feel me? No...
你知道我的意思吧？
Okay, so put one up and down.
就是这样 拿起一个 放下去
Okay.
好的
Okay, so that means...I'm the house.
对 这就是说 我是庄家
You know, you are so unsuitable for my daughter.
你和我女儿一点都不般配
Me?
我？
Yeah, you.
对 你
And that's hilarious.
真可笑
I don't...
我不...
My child comes from a whole line of revolutionaries.
我女儿来自的家族 几代人都是革命者
And you look so lost.
而你一脸茫然
She's a runner, and you a stump.
她大步向前 你却沉溺当下
What are you gonna do about this baby? Hm?
这孩子你打算怎么办？
No, I just, I wanna feel seen and...
我只是想被人看见 还有
loved and appreciated.
被人爱 被欣赏
I fuckin' carried her nine months.
我怀孩子整整九个月
And now he can just, gets to fuckin' walk around...
现在他却整天只知道围着宝宝转
and just swoonin' all fuckin' day.
看见孩子就开心得不得了
It's like she's his only girl.
就好像 他只爱女儿一个人
Like, I just no longer exist. I'm just a fuckin' piece of meat.
我就是空气 是一块肉
And sometimes, I feel crazy,
有时候我觉得自己疯了
'cause I'm just like...am I weird for being jealous of my baby?
我居然会嫉妒自己的宝宝 这正常吗？
I don't fuckin' feel seen. I don't feel love.
我感觉没人关心我 没人爱我
I feel fuckin' ugly.
我肯定变丑了
My nipples hurt. I can barely fucking produce milk.
我的胸口疼 我几乎都没有奶水了
You know, I...
我…
I'm not okay.
我感觉糟透了
Baby, where do you think you're goin', huh?
亲爱的 你大晚上去哪儿？
Where you goin' like that?
穿成这样上哪儿去？
Stop talkin' to me. I go as I please.
别跟我说话 我想去哪儿就去哪儿
You realize that we're a family now, right?
你看我们都成家了
You don't have to do this anymore.
用不着闹革命了
You realize I put myself first, right?
你知道我说过 我为自己而活
And that's what you scared of.
你就是害怕这一点
We have her now. You do get that, right?
我们都有孩子了 总不会忘了吧？
I put myself first, and I reject your lack of originality.
首先 我为自己活 其次 你的话老掉牙了
God, my lack of originality.
天啊 说我老掉牙
Will you stop with all this bullshit?
请你不要再胡扯了好吗？
Would you stop it? We're a goddamn family.
别再闹了 你和我成家了
You have her to take care of.
你有责任照顾孩子
Where the hell do you think you're goin'?
你以为你还能去哪儿？
It's okay, baby.
好啦 宝宝
It's okay, baby. It's okay.
没事的 不哭了
宝宝不哭 没事的
This is a new consciousness.
不要给我灌输你的想法
New consciousness?
我的想法？
Yeah.
对
I'm not your udder buddy.
我可不是孩子保姆
I'm not your mother.
我也不是你妈
You want your power over me,
你想要掌控我
The same reason you want your power over the world.
就像你们男人总想掌控一切
You and your crumblin' male ego...
你和你那玻璃心的大男子主义
Will never do this revolution like me.
永远不会成为这场革命的战友
Fuck outta here.
所以请滚出我的房子
Do the revolution, baby. Go do it.
那你还是闹革命去吧 再见
You got a baby?
你有孩子是吗？
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
对 有孩子
Male? Female?
男孩女孩？
She's a girl.
是个女孩
What's her name?
叫什么？
Charlene.
夏琳
Sounds like a Black girl's name.
像黑妞的名字
You like Black girls?
你喜欢黑妞吗？
I love 'em.
我超喜欢
I love them!
我爱死她们了
Get on your knees.
跪下
Get on your fuckin' knees.
给我跪下
- Don't move. - Now!
- 别动 举起手来 - 快点儿
Good job.
很好
Get your noses in the carpet.
都脸朝下趴好
My name is Junglepussy.
我叫贱女姜戈
【贱女姜戈：象征游击式反抗与自由 以挑衅性名称作为反制标识】
This is what power looks like.
看 这就是权力
See my face?
看清楚了吗？
Put it there.
装进去
- This some Set It Off shit. - Hands up.
- 我们就像《辣姐妹》一样 - 举起手
【《辣姐妹》（1996）：四位女性因贫困与不公筹划抢劫】
（联邦存款保险公司）
I don't want you. I just want your money.
我不要命 我只要你们的钱
Your money pays for my artillery,
你们的钱 会变成我的武器
my supplies,
我的补给
my transportation,
我开的车子
my dynamite,
我的炸药
my message.
我的宣言
I am what Black Power looks like.
我就是黑人力量的化身
See my face?
看清楚了吗？
See my face! I'm the French 75!
看清楚 我们是法式七五
Stop moving.
不要乱动
Stop fucking moving.
我说别动 听见了吗？
Stop fuckin' moving, man.
拜托你别动了 好吗？
【译注：黑人既为受压迫者
亦可能作为体制中尽职的执行者
突显复杂的道德两难】
All right, go.
我们走
Stop! Police!
站住 警察
Cuff the left arm, please.
拷住左手
This department doesn't do any special favors,
这个部门不会对谁网开一面
especially for Black girls.
尤其是黑妞
You're a killer, and that's the least of it.
你杀人了 这还是轻的
You'll do 30,
判个三十年
40 years in prison.
或者四十年
It's too bad you don't know anybody with sway.
可惜你不认识什么大人物
You can save me.
你可以救我
Because you're in love with me.
因为你爱上我了
Yes.
是的
And you can't live without me.
你没有我就活不下去
Can you hold me?
能抱抱我吗？
I can give you the embrace
不如我让联邦政府
of the federal government.
给你个拥抱吧
You've gotta tell me where they are, and name names.
你得说出他们在哪儿 列个名单
Don't do this.
不要这样
You have to name names, or you're gonna go to prison.
你不想坐牢 就得交代名单
Miss Minnie, do you have a car seat or a carrier?
明妮阿姨 有儿童座椅或者背带吗？
No, no, no, baby.
没有 亲爱的
These are two scanners that I've made.
这两个是我做的配对器
This one plays Melody A.
这个能播放乐曲A
This one plays Melody B.
这个能播放乐曲B
Together, they go off within 200 or 300 yards of each other,
只要它们之间的距离小于二三百米
they sync up, they'll play a main melody.
就会自动同步 合奏主旋律
- Main melody. - Okay? Somebody else has one of these,
- 主旋律 - 两人各拿一个配对器
you both know the tune, you'll be able to find each other.
就能识别出对方是自己人
- This is a trust device. - Right.
- 这个叫信任配对器 - 好
Okay? Rule of thumb with these scanners,
使用规则第一条
find somebody else out there and they happen to have one of these,
如果你见到拿着这个配对器的人
trust them with your life, okay?
就无条件信任那个人 好吗？
I'm not passing these out to just anybody.
这个我不会随便给人的
- She might be hungry. - I need some towels.
- 她可能是饿了 - 得带上毛巾
- Yeah. All right. - Miss Minnie, can you get me some towels?
- 好啦 不哭了 - 明妮阿姨 拿几条毛巾好吗？
Okay. What's wrong?
好的 怎么啦？
I know. We're going.
知道了 我们马上就出发
Get a phone or don't...
得有手机...
If you gotta get a cell, make it 1G. The early analogue stuff,
要是非得用手机 就用模拟机
【1G：1970年代末兴起的模拟手机信号 提供模拟语音移动服务】
they don't scan those frequencies anymore.
现在没人监控1G的信号了
- You'll be fine. Otherwise, no phones. - Okay.
- 所以很安全 不然就别用手机 - 好
If the towers are up, we're gonna be able to find each other in any case.
只要有信号 我们就能联系上
- All right. - Memorize everything in this envelope.
- 明白 - 记住这个信封里的东西
Burn it when you're done.
记牢之后就烧掉
You don't go to Baktan Cross right away.
不要直接去归援十字市
【归援十字市：虚构城镇 意为慈爱包容并予以支援】
You go to Denver first.
先去丹佛市
You spend a week in Denver.
在那边住上一星期
While you're in Denver,
在这一星期里
plant those decoys.
误导追查方向
When that's all clear and that job is done,
留好你要去哪里的假线索后
then you go on to Baktan Cross.
再去归援十字市
These are the new names and socials.
这是你们的新名字和社保号码
Right, so who are we supposed to be here?
好 那我们现在是谁？
You are Bob and Willa Ferguson.
你们是鲍勃·弗格森和薇拉·弗格森
【新身份：常见白人名字 便于融入与不被怀疑】
It's a mother and son who died in childbirth last month.
这是上个月去世的一对母子的名字
So we're pretending to be dead folks?
所以我们要假冒死人？
If you wanna think about it that way, yes,
要是你这么想 那就是这样
but there are bigger deaths down the line if we don't do this.
但要是不这样做 死的人会更多
I want you to think big picture here, all right?
我希望你能顾全大局
- Right. Right. - This is bigger than you or I.
- 好 - 这件事比你我都重要
This is bigger than the original Bob and Willa Ferguson, okay?
也比去世的弗格森母子更重要
Guys, you better hurry up.
你们快一点
Yeah.
好
Welcome to the world, Bob.
欢迎来到真实世界 鲍勃
Let's go!
出发吧
Big picture.
顾全大局
Got it. Yeah.
明白 是啊
Okay.
好的
Okay. Okay.
好的 没问题
You're safe.
你很安全
- I gotta go. I'm sorry, okay? - Okay.
- 我得走了 添麻烦了 - 好吧 你走吧
- I know you do, but... - I'm sorry.
- 慢走 - 拜托你们了
I know, but you not sure you wanna let her stay with us?
走吧 你确定不把宝宝留下来吗？
I gotta go, I gotta go!
我得赶快走了
I know, I know. But travel in grace.
我知道了 你路上小心
Oh, my God.
天啊 保佑他们平安吧
Here. Hold her.
帮我抱一下
- All right, I got her, I got her. - Thanks.
- 好 给我吧 - 谢谢
- Come on, baby girl, come on.
- 好孩子 过来吧 - 给你
Watch her head.
当心头
All right.
好了
Love you.
爱你
I love you.
也爱你
Take care.
保重
- Stay safe. - Okay.
- 你也是 - 走了
Home sweet home.
回到家了
We've been through all this before, but I've gotta go through it one more time.
这些你都听过 但我要再强调一遍
No contact ever with anyone from Josie and the Pussycats
不要联系任何人 特别是你那帮花瓶姐妹
【猫女乐队：源自美国漫画与动画 并有同名乐团 故事中被用作贬称】
or any of your former associates.
别去找你过去的同伙
No family. No friends.
不能见家人朋友
Don't commit any crimes.
绝不要犯罪
You will testify when we need you to testify.
需要作证的时候 我们会找你的
Look, first order of business, find a job.
你的当务之急是找一份工作
Pay your bills.
养活自己
- You good? - Mm-hmm.
- 听懂了吗？ - 嗯
Welcome to mainstream America.
欢迎成为主流美国人
Every revolution begins fightin' demons
革命一开始 我们与恶魔作战
but motherfuckers just end up fightin' themselves.
到头来 却开始自相残杀
（员工通道 顾客止步）
Hands up!
举起手来
Put your hands up over your head!
举起手来 手放在后脑勺上
She's in the back!
把你的手举起来
Get your hands up! Higher!
高一点儿
For valor in the line of duty...
他执行任务英勇无畏
and bringing justice to the vigilante group...
最终成功让暴力团伙法式七五组织
known as the French 75,
受到了法律的制裁
We are here to award
我们特此表彰
Steven J. Lockjaw
史蒂文·勒喉乔警官
with the Bedford-Forrest Medal of Honor.
为他颁发贝德福德·福雷斯特荣誉奖章
【内森·贝德福德·福雷斯特：白人至上主义者 三K党领导人】
（老娘对你没性趣）
（清仓甩卖）
（墨西哥海关）
Sixteen years later,
16年之后
the world had changed very little.
世界没有改变多少
（日语）平安二段
You're not breathing.
你的呼吸不对
Let's do it again.
再来一遍
♪ Times are hard
♪ 日子不好过
♪ You're afraid to pay the fee ♪
♪ 你害怕付账
♪ So you find yourself somebody ♪
♪ 于是你找了个
♪ Who can do the job for free ♪
♪ 愿意免费干活的人 ♪
（日语）平安二段
♪ When you need a bit of lovin' ♪
♪ 当你需要爱和关心
♪ 'Cause your man is out of town ♪
♪ 因为那个人不在家
♪ That's the time you get me runnin' ♪
♪ 于是你找到我
♪ And you know I'll be around ♪
♪ 你知道我会在你身边 ♪
♪ I'm a fool to do your dirty work, oh yeah ♪
♪ 我真是傻瓜 愿意为你干脏活 ♪
♪ I don't wanna do your dirty work no more ♪
♪ 从此我再也不想 为你干脏活 ♪
♪ I'm a fool to do your dirty work, oh yeah ♪
♪ 我真是傻瓜 愿意为你干脏活 ♪
♪ Light the candle put the lock upon the door ♪
♪ 点燃蜡烛 锁上大门
♪ You have sent the maid home early ♪
♪ 你让女佣提前回家
♪ Like a thousand times before ♪
♪ 过去你也总是这样 ♪
♪ Like the castle in its corner in a medieval game ♪
♪ 就像古老游戏棋盘上 角落里的城堡
（高中）
♪ I foresee terrible trouble ♪
♪ 我预感会有大麻烦
History class?
历史课？
♪ And I stay here just the same ♪
♪ 却还是留下来 ♪
Mm-hmm.
对
♪ I'm a fool to do your dirty work, oh yeah ♪
♪ 我真是傻瓜 愿意为你干脏活 ♪
Teachin' the right kind of history, I hope.
但愿你们教的是正经历史
Lincoln.
那是林肯？
【林肯：美国第16任总统 以废奴与维护联邦统一被视为国父级人物】
Mm-hmm.
对
I see you got all the greats here, huh?
墙上挂的伟人真不少啊
Oh, yeah.
当然
What were his intentions?
他打的什么主意？
Got Teddy Roosevelt over there. You got...
那边还有老罗斯福总统
Hope you teach about the Philippines and all that.
希望没漏掉美菲战争的事儿
【美菲战争（1899–1902）：美接管菲律宾引发的反殖民战争 伴随大量平民伤亡与殖民统治争议】
We don't get all into the details just yet,
这个年级不会细讲的
- but we don't hide from them, either. - You should.
- 但也不会刻意隐瞒 - 应该多讲
You should. Gotta tell the truth.
就应该告诉他们真相
And then you got...
我看还有
the Grand Wizard over there, right?
三K党的大头目
【大头目：三K党成立于富兰克林逝世75年后 台词为演员即兴讽刺】
Mr. Benjamin Franklin.
本杰明·富兰克林
Forefather.
我们的国父啊
Fuckin' slave owner.
可恶的奴隶主
You...
那个...
I'm afraid you can't do that here in the classroom.
抱歉 教室里不能抽烟
- Fuckin' slave owners everywhere. - Thanks.
- 真是到处都有可恶的奴隶主 - 谢谢配合
Well,
好吧
Overall, to get into it, Willa's doing really great.
总体来说 薇拉在学校表现相当好
She's a confident leader.
她很自信 也有领导力
She works hard.
她还努力学习
You can tell that she actually
看得出来
cares about being a good student, you know?
她是真心想做一个好学生
She enters class each day ready to work,
她每天来学校都活力十足
Full of energy.
期待着学知识
The other students really admire her, um...
其他学生都很佩服她
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
If I get emotional, it's just um...
我这眼泪只是...
Tears of joy, that's all.
喜极而泣
Oh.
哦
I see this is very emotional for you.
我能看出你现在很激动
I don't know...
我不知道
You know, Willa grew up without her mom.
说实话 薇拉一直没有妈妈
Her mom died when she was very young.
她妈妈在她很小的时候死了
Oh. I see.
是这样啊
So Willa never knew her mother?
薇拉从没见过妈妈？
No. She never did.
没有 从来没见过
That can be very hard on a young woman.
这姑娘太不容易了
（边境战术应对小组 拘留中心）
（7号拘留区）
（警告 围栏已通电）
（西班牙语）请帮忙
（西班牙语）帮帮忙
Sir, I have Lieutenant Skinner here to speak with you.
长官 斯金纳中尉要见您
What do you got, Skinner?
斯金纳 有什么事？
Sir,
长官
Deputy Director of Progress has orders to speak to you, sir.
优进部副主任奉上级命令 要与您谈话
Your transportation is set for 1800 hours, sir.
已经安排了车 今晚六点送您过去
You know what this is about, Skinner?
知道他有什么事吗？
- No, sir, I'm... - Well, I think I do.
- 不知道 我... - 没事 我猜到了
That'll be all, Lieutenant.
你可以出去了 中尉
Welcome, Colonel. Please follow me.
欢迎 上校 请跟我来
（非出口）
（通往酒店大堂）
（州长套房）
Have somebody tell my wife
让人告诉我妻子
I'll be down in a few minutes.
我几分钟后就下去
Colonel Lockjaw, thanks for coming.
勒喉乔上校 谢谢你过来
Sandy, great to see you.
您好 桑迪先生
Let me introduce you to Virgil Throckmorton.
认识一下维道尔·司空伯顿
Virgil, Colonel Steve Lockjaw.
维道尔 这是勒喉乔上校
Steve Lockjaw.
我叫史蒂文·勒喉乔
How do you do, Colonel?
你好 上校
My pleasure, sir.
很高兴认识您
Yeah, I'm sorry about all the espionage at the back entrance.
抱歉 还让你偷偷摸摸从后门进来
My daughter's getting married and dress was formal.
我女儿要结婚 大家都穿着礼服
So, we didn't want you to feel out of place.
我们不想让你不自在
Perfectly understandable, sir.
我完全理解 先生
Please, sit.
请坐吧
Shane Mitchell sends a hello.
尚恩·米切尔向你问好
The big dog. He still building out that garage?
尚恩老大 他还在建车库吗？
The construction project that never ends.
我看他永远都建不完
I'm sure he'll get it done. Will you give him my best?
总会完工的 请您替我带个好
- Will do. - Thank you.
- 好 - 谢谢
How was your journey from Rio Duarte?
从里奥杜尔特过来顺利吗？
Fine, sir.
很顺利
You're doing great work down there.
你在那边干得不错
Thank you very much, sir.
谢谢您 先生
Each and every day is hand-to-hand combat
移民就像汹涌的潮水
in the spread of uncontrolled migration, isn't it?
每天都是一场硬仗 对吗？
Yes, it is, sir.
您说得没错
Yeah.
是啊
Well, "You wanna save the planet, you start with immigration."
有人说“解决移民 拯救地球”
That's exactly right, sir.
完全正确 先生
You said that.
这是你说的
A few years back, after Squatting Pebble.
几年前卧石行动结束后说的
I understand you've expressed an interest in us.
我听说你对我们感兴趣
Yes, sir, I have.
是 先生
And does it honor you
你是不是很荣幸
to be considered for membership in our club?
能被提名加入我们的俱乐部？
It's a very deep honor, sir.
我深感荣幸 先生
Yes, it is.
当然是这样
Steve, we have, in the past,
史蒂文 我们在过去几年呢
Offered membership to certain members of the military.
招募了一些军方成员加入俱乐部
We found their...
我们发现他们的
Tactical battlefield expertise to be quite useful.
实战经验和专业战术相当有用
Now, our aim and your aim is the same.
你看 我们和你的目标是一致的
To find dangerous lunatics, haters
及时发现危险的疯子 恨国者
And punk trash and stop them.
地痞流氓 及时制止
No more lunatics.
再也不会有人闹事
Now, I'm not sure if you've heard or not,
我不知道你有没有听说
but Jim Kringle passed away.
吉姆·克林格去世了
【克林格：意为耶稣小孩 为英语中圣诞老人的别称】
Oh, I did hear that, yes.
我听到了消息
This means an opening.
俱乐部有空缺了
Colonel, I don't think I'm being immodest when I say
上校 我可以毫不夸张地说
that joining the Christmas Adventurers Club
如果能够加入圣诞先驱俱乐部
means that you are a superior man.
你就正式成为了高尚的人
No, not the best man, not the most intelligent,
你不是最优秀 最聪明的人
The most sophisticated, or the wisest.
也不是最见多识广和智慧的人
It just means that you are superior to other human beings,
你只是比其他人更优越 更高尚
And you shall never want for riches or the greatest of friends.
当然你会得到财富 交到最好的朋友
Now, we report to ourselves with a freedom to be creative
我们是独立运作 行事也可以机动灵活
and cut through layers of bureaucracy.
省略一些繁琐的程序
We live by the Golden Rule,
我们信奉金科玉律
in a network of like-minded men and women
目标是与志同道合的伙伴们一起
dedicated to makin' the world safe and pure.
让世界变得更安全 更纯净
What would you say to someone who believes
如果有人认为
that you have been soft
你在种族净化行动中
in your duty to racial purification?
表现出软弱动摇 你会怎么说？
I would say
我会说
they are a liar who has no business in society.
说这样话的人不配活在社会上
Or on the planet, for that matter. Mm.
也不配活在地球上
Do you presently live with a spouse?
你现在有配偶吗？
No, sir.
没有
Have you ever consulted with a mental health professional?
你有没有因为心理健康问题 咨询过医生？
No, sir.
没有
Have you ever had any bills or debts
你有没有拖欠债务
turned over to a collection agency?
被人追债？
Well, I did purchase a jet ski.
我买过一辆水上摩托
It was an evolution of the old Hummingbird Whisperdoo 238.
是悄羽蜂速238那个型号的升级款
Called the Dynamite Dolphin 335.
叫做疾爆海豚335
It was defective.
它性能有缺陷
I abstained from payment. I'd do it again. I have no regrets.
我就拒绝了付款 但我一点也不后悔
Okay.
好的
Have you ever knowingly engaged
你有没有公开参与过
in any acts of terrorism against this country?
任何针对美国的恐怖活动？
No, sir.
没有
Have you ever engaged in an interracial relationship?
你有没有经历过跨种族的恋爱关系？
No, sir.
没有
And you are American-born by gentile?
你是美国出生的非犹太人？
Yes, sir.
是的
Now, to avoid any misunderstanding,
有一点我要说清楚
we require absolute secrecy
你申请加入俱乐部期间
through the initiation process
必须对此事完全保密
to judge how serious and unselfish you are.
这是为了测试你的无私和忠诚
- You understand? - Mm-hmm.
- 明白吗？ - 嗯
And to be considered to a vote,
另外 想要成为候选成员
you must submit to a voluntary vulnerability study.
你必须自愿接受一项背景审查
This identifies anything problematic in your character.
用来查明你个人可能有的任何问题
What could be a problem?
我能有什么问题吗？
I don't know.
我不知道
What could be a problem?
你有问题吗？
Absolutely nothing.
绝对不会有
We wanna know who we're standing with.
我们需要了解你是否可靠
Sure.
当然
Now,
审查是由
It's a Double Yankee White Inquisitions Completum.
宗审委员会做的全套纯血美国白人背景审查
So if you have any doubt as to your ability
所以 如果你怀疑自己的
to qualify in body or character
身体和品格无法胜任
as a member of the Christmas Adventurers Club,
圣诞先驱俱乐部成员一职
now you have an opportunity to say so.
请你现在就提出来
Do you wish to withdraw?
你要放弃申请吗？
No, sir.
不 先生
Do you submit yourself?
你愿意接受审查吗？
Yes, sir. I submit myself.
是的 我愿意接受审查
Very well, then.
非常好
Now Sandy and I have to get down to cut the cake.
我和桑迪要去切蛋糕了
Congratulations on your daughter's wedding.
恭喜您 祝您女儿新婚快乐
Thank you.
谢谢你
We'll be in touch.
保持联系
Thank you.
谢谢
Steve.
史蒂文
Thank you, sir. Thank you, Sandy.
谢谢您 桑迪先生
Maybe starting to see how corrupt to the core
“你们也许已经看清了
this whole fucking charade is.
“这场闹剧腐烂到骨子里了”
This great, noble experiment in self-government.
“我们伟大的民主共和政府
Bought and sold by billionaires.
“被亿万富豪收买出卖 随意操纵
The Davos crowd.
“那群达沃斯佬
【达沃斯佬：出席达沃斯论坛的精英 意指脱离民众的权力阶层】
Openly racist, fucking Bell Curve Nazis.
“都是公开种族主义者 信奉钟形理论的纳粹”
【《钟形曲线》（1994）：争议著作 结论主张智力与种族相关】
It's bedtime for democracy, comrades. Good night.
“同志们 民主要沉睡了 道晚安吧”
So you're feeling like maybe your mind is starting to erode? Good.
“你感觉自己的心智在被侵蚀吗？
B-Q-W-5-L-P-A, go ahead.
“我们来听听其他电台是怎么说的”
This is happening on the ground
“我们的斗争已经开始了
through coordinated effort,
“我们要有意识 有组织
And strategic lines of resistance...
“有策略地反抗压迫”
Every day, working through dedicated teamwork
“我们要每天团结一致 并肩战斗
to take it directly
“让那些大资本家
to the capitalist overlords,
“见识到革命的力量”
Who are extracting value from your life this very second.
“别忘了资本家每时每刻都在吸我们的血”
Go ahead.
“继续”
What, you think this is Facebook?
“你们以为在网上喊喊口号
This is gonna happen on your Instagram?
“发发朋友圈就是斗争吗？”
（可网上购车票）
It's gonna happen on a hashtag somewhere?
“挂个话题标签就能胜利吗？”
I think not.
“不是这样的”
And don't forget, while you're doing it,
“斗争的时候 也请不要忘记
that this is a nation that gives asylum.
“这个国家应当给予外来者庇护”
Don't think they're separate.
这些事情不是孤立的
Don't break them apart. They're not...
要联系起来看 应该要...
What the fuck?
你要干什么？
"QST, QST, QST!
通告 通告 重要通告
Attention, all sanctuary stations.
所有庇护站点 请注意
Billy Goat is in the wind.
“倔山羊被风吹走了”
Repeat, Billy Goat is in the wind.
重复“倔山羊被风吹走了”
Implement plan Snap, Crackle, Pop.
立即执行“霹雳”计划
Repeat, plan Snap, Crackle, Pop.
重复 执行“霹雳”计划
Repeat, implement plan Snap, Crackle, Pop."
QST, QST, QST!
“通告 通告 重要通告
（紧急情况下通告内容）
Attention, all sanctuary stations.
“所有庇护站点 请注意”
Billy Goat is in the wind.
“‘倔山羊被风吹走了’
Repeat, Billy Goat is in the wind.
“重复 ‘倔山羊被风吹走了’”
Implement plan Snap, Crackle, Pop.
“立即执行‘霹雳’计划
Repeat, plan Snap, Crackle, Pop.
“重复 执行‘霹雳’计划”
What's up, my man?
你好啊
You got my guy?
人带来了吗？
Any SSE in the car?
车里有痕迹吗？
- No. - No?
- 没有 - 好
（里奥杜尔特营地 最高戒备）
Come here, dirtbag.
给我出来 人渣
Howard Sommerville.
霍华德·萨默威尔
How are you?
你好吗？
Good.
很好
The French 75.
“法式七五组织”
The Resistance.
“抵抗运动”
The Gringo Coyote?
“外来土狼”
Billy Goat?
“倔山羊”
Done your homework.
你查的挺细啊
Good.
很好
Take a look around. Take it all in.
看看周围 好好看看
Do you need anything?
需要什么吗？
I'm fine.
不需要
A drink?
要喝水吗？
I'm okay.
不用了
You're still alive. That's a good sign, right?
你还活着 这是好事
Seem to be.
大概是吧
Yeah. Do you know why you're still alive?
对 你知道为什么吗？
You tell me.
那要问你
I will tell you.
那我就说了
I need you to tell me where Baby Charlene is,
我需要你告诉我夏琳的信息
what's her name, where does she live?
她现在叫什么？住在哪儿？
I need to know where The Rocket Man lives.
我需要知道“火箭男”住在哪里
I need to know his name.
他现在叫什么？
- Okay. - Ghetto Pat.
- 好吧 - 我说的是“穷鬼帕特”
Okay. I can cooperate.
好吧 我愿意合作
Their names are Fred Flintstone
他们一个叫摩登原始人
and Arthur Fonzarelli
一个叫欢乐时光
and their address is Alpha Centauri.
住在天涯边海角上
【被审问者故意报出的流行文化虚构姓名】
I love it. I love it.
太幽默了 我喜欢
Motherfucker's sittin' on plastic in a container,
他自己都泥菩萨过河了
he's still got jokes.
还不忘讲笑话
I just want you to know that I'm not scared.
我只想让你知道 我不害怕
I appreciate that.
我很佩服你
If I was in your shoes, I wouldn't be scared, either.
如果换成是我 我也不会害怕
I just don't know if your sister would feel that way.
只是不知道你妹妹会不会害怕
What's his sister's name?
他妹妹叫什么来着？
Pamela.
帕梅拉
Oh, no more jokes?
不讲笑话了吗？
What are their names and where do they live?
他们叫什么？住在哪儿？
Their names are Bob and Willa Ferguson.
他们叫鲍勃·弗格森和薇拉·弗格森
They're up in Baktan Cross.
住在归援十字市
Baktan Cross.
归援十字市
Make me a reason to deploy in that town.
找个理由让我去那边出任务
- Drugs and tacos. - Got it.
- 打击贩毒和拉丁裔移民 - 明白
And get all the intel on the gathering spots,
帮我搜集一些当地情报 就是
the hotspots for teenyboppers.
小年轻都喜欢去的地方
On it.
遵命
Shep.
小牧
Shep. Hey,
come here, come here.
过来 到这儿来
Where'd you...
去哪儿啦？
Come, come with me.
到这儿来
How ya doin'?
你开不开心呀？
Get it! Shep!
去捡 小牧
Shep.
小牧
Gentlemen, this is Operation Boot Heel.
各位 欢迎参与铁踏行动
Our AO is Baktan Cross.
行动地点是归援十字市
This is a sanctuary city
这是一座庇护城市
full of thousands of wet 'n stinkies.
到处是臭烘烘的拉丁裔
We have a TST operation
我们的行动必须要快
to capture two HVIs.
抓捕两名重要目标
Adult male, Bob Ferguson.
成年男性鲍勃·弗格森
Female juvenile, Willa Ferguson,
少女薇拉·弗格森
age 16, the daughter.
16岁 是他女儿
We bag-and-tag the male. We apprehend the female.
男的裹尸装回来 女的要留活口
（警察）
Intel update.
情报更新
Baktan High School dance today, 1800.
归援高中今天有舞会 傍晚六点
Grades nine through 12.
九到十二年级参加
Break, break, break, net call one-three.
注意 注意 全体注意 呼叫幺三
We're gonna split the team.
我们分组行动
Cell One to the high school.
一组去学校
Cell Two to the residence with me.
二组随我去目标住处
（警察）
Good evening, gentlemen. Special Agent Toejam.
各位下午好 我是特工托杰姆
Our main target tonight is Rimhorn's Chicken Lickin' Frozen Food Farm.
今晚的主要目标 是霍氏香香鸡速冻食品厂
HUMINT reporting has led us to believe Chicken Lickin' is a front
情报显示 香香鸡厂只是幌子
for a large-scale heroin distribution operation within the AO.
实际上 它是这一带的 大规模海洛因分销点
BTR, your main effort, you are tasked with the clearing and securing
边境战术应对小组 你们的任务是
of Chicken Lickin' Frozen Food Farm in order to destroy
搜查并控制香香鸡速冻食品厂
heroin distribution operations within the AO.
以捣毁该区域内的海洛因分销窝点
Simultaneously, local law enforcement,
同时当地警方也会行动
You will clear and secure Blatski's Tires,
你们负责搜查并控制布拉茨基轮胎行
Raliberto's Mexican Restaurant on Old California Road,
老加州大街上的拉里贝托墨西哥餐厅
Tiburón's Taco Shack in the Baktan Mall,
归援商场里的巨鲨墨西哥夹饼店
and the gas station on J and Boiler Street.
还有杰及工业大街上的加油站
This is a sanctuary city
这是个庇护城市
for thousands of wet bodies.
有几千拉丁裔
Expect the local populace to be
当地的居民很可能
sympathetic and supportive
会同情 甚至包庇
to the criminal organizations we are targeting tonight, gentlemen.
我们今晚要突击的犯罪组织
Thank you.
多谢
You're hungover,
你还没醒酒
and you got home at 3:00 in the morning.
凌晨三点才回家
Where were you?
你去哪儿了？
Where, what?
去哪儿？
This isn't even warm, sweetie.
宝贝 你也不帮我热一下
Where were you?
你去哪儿了？
Where was I?
我去哪儿？
I was...
我去了 我...
Well, I specifically told you where I was.
我特地告诉过你我去了哪儿
You asked me that. I told you where I was.
你问过我 我也回答了你
I was at the Rustic Inn with the old band.
我去了乡土酒馆 听乐队演奏
You remember our old band, right?
是我们以前爱听的乐队 记得吗？
The old band, sweetie. A Block Past Normal.
就是他们 正常街区外
You remember Albert?
记得艾伯特吗？
Yeah.
记得
Turns out,
我才知道
Albert bought all this old equipment
艾伯特买了一些旧设备
from Steely Dan's old studio
都是史提利·丹乐队的录音室用过的
【史提利·丹乐队：1970年代美国摇滚与爵士融合乐队】
to try to get that sort of vintage, you know,
他买下这些就是为了玩复古
that sort of crackling tube sound.
追求所谓的真空管音色
You don't need any of that stuff anymore.
现在谁要听这种东西？
He brought out a computer program.
他还买了个电脑软件
Boom, with the press of a button--
说是只要按一下按钮
How'd you get home?
你怎么回家的？
What do you mean?
什么意思？
How did you get home?
你怎么回家的？
Well, with my car.
我开车回来的
You drove?
醉驾了？
So what are you, my babysitter? What, what, what...
怎么？难道你是我的保姆吗？
Yeah.
对啊
I know how to drink and drive, honey. I know what I'm doin'.
我会喝酒 也会开车 我能照顾好自己
- I didn't have that much. - Dad.
- 我也没喝那么多 - 爸爸
What?
什么？
干吗？
What?
说呀
I don't wanna be your babysitter.
我也不想当你的保姆
I don't wanna worry if you wrapped
我不想天天操心你有没有
your cararound a telephone pole.
把车撞到电线杆子上
Well, I didn't wrap my--
我没有撞到电线...
I didn't ask for this.
我不是这个意思
That's just how the cards were rolled out for me.
可我怎么躺上这种事情？
It's...
不对
It's "dice," sweetie.
是摊上
What?
什么？
It's not "cards." You don't roll cards. It's dice.
不是躺上这种事 是摊上这种事
Fuck off, Bob.
滚一边去 鲍勃
Just fuck off with that, okay?
别再扯这些了 好吗？
Grow up.
成熟点儿
Wow. Okay.
好吧
Well, you... Look. I like the way you're standin' up for yourself.
我想说 你能表达自己的观点
I'm proud of ya, honey,
这样非常好
but the way you, uh,
但是有时候
Speak to your father sometimes, it's just...
你对你爸说话的方式有点...
I don't know. You're right.
你说得也对
You should tell me what you think, always.
以后多跟我坦诚相待
Never hold anything back from me.
任何事情都不要瞒我
What the fuck is wrong with you?
你到底是有什么毛病？
You're right. That's somethin' I gotta remember.
说得对 我得记住 我这人有毛病
And I fuck up sometimes.
时不时还会搞砸事情
Whoa. Who's this?
谁来了？
Who's that?
那是谁？
Who is that?
是什么人？
They're just my friends.
只是我的朋友
And they just,
朋友？
They have a red car like that, just drivin'...
还开个红色的车
Little loud, don't you think?
太张扬了吧？
It's just a car.
一辆车而已
- And you told 'em they could do that? - Yes.
- 是你让他们开过来的？ - 对
Told 'em to come to the house?
到我们家门口？
Yes!
怎么了
Now, who's the one with the lipstick?
那个涂口红的是谁？
What's that one's name?
叫什么名字？
Bobo.
波波
Bobo. Now, is that a he or a she or a they?
波波 这是男的？女的？还是别的什么性别？
Dad, come on.
行了 老爸
No, are they transitioning? I wanna know if...
我只是想知道 这位是在性别过渡还是…
They're nonbinary.
人家是是非二元性别
【非二元性别：不完全认同传统男女二元分类的性别身份】
Okay, I just wanna be polite. All right.
好吧 我只是想确定一下称呼
It's not that hard! "They, them."
没什么好确定的 用中性词
And who's this little fuckin' freak at the door?
门口那个臭小子又是谁？
Probably Bluto.
大概是布罗托
They're just comin' to my house like this, huh?
就这样登门的？
Yes!
怎么了？
All right.
没事
Is that your date to the dance?
这小子是不是你的舞伴？
- My friend. - Okay.
- 是我朋友 - 好吧
You're not goin' anywhere with your goddamn friend
你哪儿也不许去
until you take it.
除非拿上这个
Take it!
快拿上
（信任配对器）
Yep. Put it in your pocket.
对 放在口袋里
I don't wanna put it in my pocket.
我不想放在口袋里
Put it in your garter or whatever you got.
那就放在吊袜带里面好了
My fucking garter?
谁还穿吊袜带？
What? Mother...
什么？你这...
What's up, homie?
你有什么事？
Hey, how's it goin'?
嘿 你好吗？
You cool?
你没事吧？
Yeah. I was just here to pick up Willa.
没事 我就是来接薇拉
Yeah, yeah.
对 对
You normally knock that loud at somebody's house like that?
你平时敲别人家门都是这么大声吗？
- Uh, yeah. - Yeah, give us a sec, homie.
- 是 - 耐心等着
Put it in... You got a purse?
可以放在...你带包吗？
This is non-negotiable!
你必须拿上它
Put it in your purse!
放在你包里
Nobody's coming to get you, Bob.
没人会来抓你的 鲍勃
You know that, right?
你自己也知道
That's what you think.
那是你以为
What's up, guys?
你们好吗？
You guys cool?
都不错吧？
- You guys hangin'? - Yep.
- 你们是朋友吗？ - 是
Goin' to the dance?
要去舞会吗？
Yeah, it's cool.
好 没问题
Listen, I'm gonna tell you somethin',
听着 记住
whatever you do to her,
如果你敢伤害薇拉
I'm gonna do that exact same thing
我就会对你以牙还牙
to your entire fuckin' family.
还会报复你们全家
I'm not fuckin' around.
我说真的
Wait, what?
你说什么？
Dad?
爸爸
I'm just tellin' ya.
我就是随便聊聊
We're talkin' about freedom, baby.
我们正探讨自由呢
We're talkin' about freedom.
我们在探讨自由
Freedom's a funny thing, isn't it?
自由这东西真怪
When ya have it,
拥有的时候
you... you don't appreciate it,
你并不珍惜
and when you miss it, it's gone.
等到你渴望自由 它砰一下就没了
It's just gone.
彻底没了
Poof!
砰
Okay.
好吧
There's a quinoa casserole with Frosted Flakes in the oven.
烤箱里有藜麦焗烤糖霜玉米片
Don't leave it on.
别忘了
Got it. Have fun, homie.
遵命 玩得开心 小子
All right.
谢谢
All right, cool.
好 去吧
Let go of him.
快放开他
Yo!
喂
Yeah?
什么？
Not you, ese.
跟你没关系 伙计
Her, I'm talkin' to her. Get in the fuckin' car.
我在跟她说话 快上车吧
Say it.
说吧
Say it, baby.
说那句话 亲爱的
Love you, Bob.
爱你 鲍勃
Love you, too.
我也爱你
Fuckin' freaks.
没个正形儿
Does anyone have a charger? My phone's dead.
谁有充电器？我手机没电了
No. I love your skirt.
没有 你裙子真好看
Thank you. I love your dress.
谢谢 你的也很漂亮
Thanks.
谢谢
Your dad's aggro, bro.
话说你老爸也太凶了吧
He's fuckin' paranoid, okay?
他有被害妄想
Okay.
好吧
This is...
看那边
♪ Callin' a young Sheck Wes' phone ♪
♪ 教练打电话给年轻的谢克·韦斯
♪ Where's Ali with the motherfuckin' dough ♪
♪ 阿里怎么还不把钱拿来 ♪
By the tennis court.
就停在网球场旁
Wait, who got that video?
等等 谁手上有视频？
And...no. That's not even the best part.
然后 最精彩的还没讲呢
- And she literally threw up on it. - Oops. Sorry.
- 然后 她直接就吐在车上了 - 借过
- What? - Yes!
- 什么？ - 真的
Wait, do you think someone out there has a video of that?
等等 有人把这段拍下来了吗？
- Wait. I bet they do. - Wait.
- 肯定有人录 - 真的
We need to go find Tom and Ron.
快去问问汤姆和罗恩
Baby, don't be scared.
亲爱的 不要害怕
All right? Now, I'm gonna say it.
明白吗？我要说暗号了
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies and Hooterville Junction."
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
【新青入乡：指城市出身者下乡格格不入 亦可指新获绿卡或新移民 源自美剧《绿野情》】
Come on, baby, say it back to me.
来吧 亲爱的 回应我
【暴富新贵：指突得财富却格格不入的新土豪 象征阶级反转 源自美剧《贝弗利山人》】
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, Hooterville Junction."
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
"Will no longer be so goddamn relevant."
“上层建筑再也不重要了”
【中枢小镇：源自流行文化中的虚构城镇 象征剧情交会与相互作用的舞台】
"And women will not care if Dick finally got down with Jane on Search for Tomorrow."
“洗脑的肥皂剧也洗不掉她们的关切”
"Because Black people will be in the streets..."
“因为黑人会走上街头”
"Looking for a brighter day."
“带着未来的希冀”
"The revolution will not be televised."
“革命永远不会被喉舌转播”
My dad said if anyone said that shit to me
我爸说如果有人对我念这段话
to trust 'em with my life.
就无条件信任对方
All right, right now, you need to.
现在你必须信任我
'Cause you're in trouble, Willa.
因为你有麻烦了 薇拉
All right? Now, there's an SOS signal out.
明白吗？有人发了求救信号
I am here to help.
我是来帮你的
But we have to leave here right away.
但我们得马上离开这儿
Look, I knew your mom
听着 我认识你妈妈
and your dad.
还有你爸爸
I know you have a lot of questions, and I'll answer 'em later,
你一定有很多问题 我会回答的
but right now, we have to roll.
但现在我们得快走
Will you leave here with me?
你愿意跟我走吗？
Where?
去哪儿？
Anywhere but here.
只要不是这儿
'Kay.
好
Okay.
好的
You have to stay by my side,
你必须待在我身边
and you have to do exactly as I say. Do you understand?
严格执行我说的话 明白了吗？
Yes, ma'am.
是 长官
Do you have a phone on you?
你带手机了吗？
No.
没有
All right.
很好
Come on, baby, let's go.
走吧 亲爱的
♪ Oh don't you dare look back ♪
♪ 不许回头
♪ Just keep your eyes on me ♪
♪ 眼睛看着我
♪ I said, "You're holding back" ♪
♪ 我说你在犹豫
♪ She said "Shut up and dance with me" ♪
♪ 她说闭嘴 和我跳舞吧 ♪
Wait, what about my dad?
那我爸怎么办？
He'll know what to do. He trained for this.
不用担心他 他受过训练
Oh, God. Come on.
我的天啊 快点儿
Come on, baby, come on!
快 使劲儿跑
Go, go, go, go, go!
走 走 走 走
One-Three-Echo, One-Three-Delta. Lights, music.
幺三戊 幺三戊 开灯 关音乐
♪ This woman is my destiny she said... ♪
♪ 这个女人是我的命中注定 她说道 ♪
Have you get all these kids in the center of the gym.
你跟他们说 都站到场地中间
Tell 'em everything's gonna be okay.
告诉他们不要惊慌
（警察）
I need to get 'em set down, and I gotta talk to 'em.
都安静一下 我要说几句话
Everybody, listen!
大家听着
I need you guys to stand up and join everybody else on the court.
所有人都站起来 站在球场中央
（法语）“还要为使我们同胞染上恶习负责”
（《阿尔及尔之战》）
【《阿尔及尔之战》（1966）：再现阿尔及利亚争取独立的反殖民斗争】
- Do you know Willa Ferguson? - No.
- 认识薇拉·弗格森吗？ - 不认识
- Seven eight nine ten. - Do you know Willa Ferguson?
- 七八九十 - 认识薇拉·弗格森吗？
- Let's get in line. - No.
- 你们来排队 - 不认识
Do you know Willa Ferguson?
认识薇拉·弗格森吗？
"Only then
“只有那时
can we take on our real enemy."
才能战胜真正的敌人”
"National Liberation Army."
“全民解放阵线”
（法语）“第二十四号公报”
（法语）“阿尔及利亚人民殖民地政府...”
Yeah?
喂？
Bob?
鲍勃
Who's this?
是哪位？
"We have trouble ahead. And the road isn't clear."
“我们有麻烦了 路上不太平”
Wait, excuse me?
你说什么？
Who is this?
你 你是哪位？
- Who is this? - I need the greeting code, Bob.
- 你是谁？ - 请你背诵暗号
Oh, fuck.
完蛋
Well, I don't remember the fuckin' greeting code
我已经不记得暗号是什么
because I got a little bit high.
因为我有点嗨
And I... it's been fuckin' years,
那个 已经好多年了
so you gotta help me out here with this.
你能不能提示我一下？
I don't...
我不太 那个
You're gonna have to think.
你得自己想
Right.
也对
Hm. Okay. "The..."
好
"The sun, the sun..."
“太阳 太阳...”
Think.
好好想
"The sunrise. Sunrise,
太阳 是“日出 日出”
sunrise in the west." Right?
“日出在西方”对吗？
Ah.
哎
The campus has been raided
校园被突袭了
and the Billy Goat has been taken.
他们带走了倔山羊
Billy Goat is Howard Sommerville,
倔山羊就是萨默威尔
so Howard Sommerville has been taken.
所以霍华德·萨默威尔被带走了
He's been taken or killed.
也许还被干掉了
What's goin' on?
到底是怎么回事？
Taken. Yesterday.
被带走了 昨天的事
And it gets worse.
现在情况更糟
"The Hammer is loose and en route to Baktan Cross."
“铁锤出动了 来到了归援十字市”
Steve Lock...
你是说 史蒂文...
Steve fucking Lockjaw?
那个史蒂夫·勒喉乔出动了吗？
What in the motherfucking fuck?
怎么会闹成这个样子？搞什么？
How could it get any fuckin' worse than that?
情况还能更糟吗？
- You're saying Steve Lockjaw... -It's high alert, Bob.
- 史蒂夫·勒喉乔 什么？ - 你要保持高度警惕
Nothing is secure. Everything is wrong.
一切都不安全 一切都不对劲
No one is above suspicion.
任何人都不能信任
No, no, no. Slow down. Okay?
不不不 慢一点儿 好吗？
My daughter...
我女儿
my fuckin' daughter left the house.
我女儿现在不在家里
She's not in the house with me,
她没有和我在一起
so you gotta give me more information.
你得多告诉我一些信息
Willa's secure.
薇拉很安全
Lady Champagne and her team have extracted Willa.
香槟女士的小队已经把薇拉接走了
- She's safe. - Good.
- 她很安全 - 好
Okay, good. Keep her there.
很好 就让她待在那儿
The rendezvous points are the same as they've ever been.
集合地点还是和之前一样
We'll be seeing you.
到时候见
I'll be seeing... Well, okay. Tell me the rendezvous point.
到时候 等等 集合地点在哪儿？
What's the...
到底是…
Hello?
喂？
What's the fuckin' rendezvous... Hello?
你们要在哪儿集合？喂？
Fuck!
可恶
Fuck.
糟了
Okay.
好吧
Okay, Bob.
好吧 鲍勃
Don't panic.
先冷静
Don't fuckin' panic, Bob.
不要慌 鲍勃
Keep your shit together.
不要乱了阵脚
Don't get fuckin' paranoid, man.
你要保持理智
Don't get fuckin' paranoid. Do what you gotta do.
镇定 镇定 想想该怎么办
Okay, step one, step one, step one.
好的 第一步先做什么？
Open doorway, right.
进右手门
（警察）
Initial clearance complete. Conducting back clear.
初步排查完成 正在进一步检查
Clear.
安全
Kitchen. Living room. Get the back.
检查厨房 还有客厅 你去后面
I got a tunnel!
发现地道
Tunnel!
地道？
God damn it. What do you think?
真见鬼 你怎么看？
He's a bomber.
他是个炸弹狂人
Gas.
拿瓦斯
Cover.
盖上
No, no!
不 糟了
Oh, God!
呛死了
（勇气 敬意 荣誉）
（瑟吉奥·圣卡洛斯忍者学院 加州归援十字市）
（卫生间）
（保健品大促销）
（公共电话）
Come on, come on.
快点 快点 快接
"Rise and shine."
“日上三竿”
Okay...
对
"Bat an eyelash."
“眨眼之间”
"Good morning."
“早上好”
"There are no hands on the clock."
“钟上没有指针”
"Why?"
“怎么回事？”
"Because they're not needed."
“因为没有必要”
"What time is it?"
“那现在是几点？”
Ah, fuck.
见鬼
You know,
好吧 说实话
I don't remember that part, all right?
我不太记得这段了
Let's just not nitpick over the password stuff.
一个暗号而已 拜托别太严格
Look, this is Bob Ferguson, all right?
我就是鲍勃·弗格森
You just called my house.
你们刚给我来过电话
Let's cut the shit.
就别对暗号了
I need the rendezvous point.
我要知道集合地点
"What time is it?"
“那现在是几点？”
Look, Steve Lockjaw just attacked my home.
听着 史蒂文·勒喉乔闯进了我家
I lost my daughter.
我女儿也不在我身边
- This is Bob Ferguson. Do you understand?  -Right. Yes.
- 我是鲍勃·弗格森 你明白吗？ - 嗯
I don't remember any more of this...
我真的不记得什么暗…
I don't remember any more of this code speak, all right?
我想不起来暗号是什么了 好吗？
Let's just get on with it. What is the rendezvous point?
说正事吧 集合地点在哪儿？
Okay, I need you to give me the time.
可以 但你要告诉我现在是几点
You motherfucker. You fuckin' with me?
死脑筋是吧 耍我是吧？
Are you fuckin' with me, motherfucker?
你觉得这样很好玩吗？
You just called me.
你们刚找过我
This is Bob Ferguson. You understand that?
我是鲍勃·弗格森 听见了吗？
Somebody from the resistance or the French 75
抵抗组织或者法式七五的人
just called my house. Just now!
刚给我打过电话 就刚才
"What time is it" is a key question of the underground movement, okay?
“那现在是几点？”是接头的关键问题
Studying the texts is essential.
记住暗号和代码非常重要
I don't remember any more of this code speak.
可是我真的不记得这套暗号了
I only remember half of this shit,
我只记得一半
and this stupid fuckin' hotline, which is a fuckin' miracle.
凑巧记住了这个电话号码 简直是奇迹
So stop fuckin' with me
所以别再胡扯了
and give me the fuckin' rendezvous point.
快点儿把集合地点告诉我
Well, maybe you should have studied the rebellion text a little harder.
你当初学暗号手册时应该认真一点儿
No, no, you called me.
不 是你们找的我
- Do you understand that, you fuckin' retard? - Sir...
- 听懂了没有？你个白痴 - 先生
You called me!
是你们找我
I need to find my daughter.
我要去见我女儿
Well, then call us back when you have the time.
等确定了是几点 再来电话吧
Did you, you just...
什么？你…
Did you just fuckin' hang up on me,
居然敢挂我电话
you fuckin' liberal fuckin' prick?
自由派的大混蛋
You...
可恶
（西班牙语）- 警察 - 警察
（警察 边境战术应对小组）
（西班牙语）- 都出去 - 排队走 快点
Okay, let's go!
快点
Let's go, let's go, everybody, let's go!
快走快走 所有人都走
What are you doin'?
干什么呢？
Hands up, on your knees! On your knees!
举起手 跪下去 跪下去
Get your hands up! Police! Turn around!
举起手来 跪在地上
Reina.
蕾娜
（西班牙语）嗨 瑟吉奥 你在哪儿？
I'm at work.
我在工作
（西班牙语）你听到消息了吗？
With what?
什么消息？
（西班牙语）移民局的人来了
（西班牙语）把香香鸡厂的人都带走了
（西班牙语）我看下一个就是我们
Why do you say that?
为什么这样说？
（西班牙语）因为西尔维娅刚给我打电话
（西班牙语）说是马科斯告诉她的
（西班牙语）他们把轮胎店和加油站的人 也全带走了
Hang on a sec.
你等一下
Yeah, can I help you?
你有什么事吗？
Bob.
是我鲍勃
Bob. Ferguson, yeah.
鲍勃·弗格森 是你
（私人定制课程 学习柔道强身健骨）
- You okay? - I need your help, Sensei.
- 你还好吗？ - 帮帮我 大师
- Okay. - I need your help, man.
- 好 - 你一定要帮我
You still there?
你还在吗？
（敬意）
What time do you get off work?
- （西班牙语）在 - 你几点下班？
（西班牙语）一点下班
（西班牙语）你什么时候到家？
I'm coming. Call Marisela and tell her I'm on my way.
很快就到 跟玛丽塞拉说一声
（西班牙语）你在哪儿？
I'm basically in the car.
我就快上车了
（西班牙语）所有人都要转移是吗
Yes.
对
I'm gonna call Esperanza,
我先给埃斯佩兰萨打个电话
and I'll call you back, okay?
再给你回电 好吗？
Okay. Bye.
好 再见
（西班牙语）好吧 拜拜
Bob! We gotta go.
鲍勃 该走了
（敬意）
I need a weapon, man!
我需要武器
All you got is goddamn nunchucks here!
你这儿只有一堆没用的双节棍
You know where I can get a gun?
你知道哪儿有枪吗？
Shit.
糟了
Shit. God damn it. Shit.
又来了 可恶
Bob, what's going on?
出什么事了？
It's MKU. MKU, man, they're everywhere right now!
是人类联盟 他们的人到处都是
- They're everywhere. - MKU? MKU what?
- 躲都躲不开 - 人类联盟什么？
They busted open my door.
他们炸开了我家大门
They're comin' after me and Willa right now. Right now.
还到处找我和薇拉 就现在
That's heavy metal, bro.
那可真够受的
Yeah.
是啊
Hey. Where is she?
嘿 薇拉在哪儿？
I don't know. I gotta charge my phone to find out.
不知道 我得先给这个手机充电
Here, use my phone.
用我的手机
I can't, I can't. They'll trace that phone.
不行 会被追踪的
I gotta use my phone.
我得用这个手机
Let's do that at my place, huh? We gotta go.
去我家弄吧 我们得走了
Your place?
你家？
Yeah.
对
You got a gun at your place?
你家里有枪吗？
I'll get you a gun.
我给你找一把
- You have a gun, right? - Okay? Yes.
- 你有枪 对吗？ - 好吗？对
Okay.
好吧
Right now, it's a goddamn roundup.
他们现在要来个一网打尽
I gotta deal with this shit.
我得做点什么
Okay. Yeah, let's, let's...
好的 对 我们
Let's take that to go. Come on.
我们 把手机带好
- Let's go to your place. - Come on.
- 我们去你家 - 走吧
Let's go to your place.
去你家
I'll charge my phone. You got a gun there.
充电 拿枪
Bob, Bob, Bob.
鲍勃 鲍勃 先等一下
What? What?
什么？干什么？
Get off the tatami.
别绷得这么紧 好吗？
- Okay. Yeah.
- 好吗？ - 好的
Okay. Listen.
好的 听我的
Breathe.
深呼吸
All right.
好
Okay? Cool out.
好吗？冷静
Ocean waves. Ocean waves.
心如止水 平静 平静
Ocean waves.
心如止水
Let's go. Let's go.
走吧 我们走
I'll follow you. Come on.
我陪着你呢 来吧
（西班牙语）老天保佑你 埃斯佩兰萨
（西班牙语）地下室的门开着
（西班牙语）我二十分钟后到
Got a little Latino Harriet Tubman situation going on at my place.
我家就像是个拉丁裔的“地下铁路”
【哈莉特·塔布曼与地下铁路：女性废奴领袖 领导“地下铁路”助数百人逃离奴役】
All legit, from the heart.
发自内心的自愿帮助
No cash.
不收钱
Here, use my phone.
用我的手机
No, no. No, no, man,
不不 不行
they trace that.You understand?
会被追踪的 懂吗？
They trace those calls.
通话会被监听
What's with the shades?
干吗戴墨镜？
Fuck.
见鬼
Look, me and Willa's mom,
听着 我和薇拉她妈妈
We used to run around and do some real bad shit together, all right?
过去我们很不安分 到处闹事
We were part of the French 75.
我们是法式七五的成员
They got her, now they're comin' after us.
她妈妈以前被抓了 现在又来抓我们
Fuck.
真见鬼
You're a bad hombre, Bob.
那你够坏的啊 鲍勃
Sit down.
坐下
（人类联盟野战行动 边境战术应对小组）
I'm Agent Danvers. How are you?
我是丹佛斯特工 你好吗？
Great.
很好
Great. What's your name?
好 你叫什么？
Bluto.
布罗托
Bluto. Nice to meet you, Bluto.
布罗托 很高兴认识你
Do ya mind if I have your phone? Go ahead and unlock it for me.
能看下你的手机吗？请你解锁一下
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey, sorry for crashin' the party like we did
嘿 抱歉闯进了你们的派对
but we have a few questions we wanna ask ya.
但我们有几个问题想问你
Is that all right with you?
你愿意回答吗？
Sure.
可以
You're shakin'. Are you okay?
你在发抖 还好吗？
I'm fine.
我没事
You nervous?
你紧张了？
Little bit.
有一点
Do you need anything?
需要什么吗？
No, we're good.
不用了
If you tell me the truth,
只要你说实话
You're outta here in ten seconds.
马上就可以离开这儿
Yes, sir.
是 长官
If you lie to me, we're gonna have some problems.
你要是撒谎 就会有麻烦
Yes, sir.
是 长官
- You know Willa Ferguson, right? - I do.
- 你认识薇拉·弗格森吧？ - 认识
How do you know her?
关系怎么样？
We're good friends.
我们是好朋友
Okay. Do you know where she is right now?
好的 你知道她在哪儿吗？
I'm not sure.
不太清楚
When's the last time you saw her?
最后一次见到她是什么时候？
I saw her at the dance.
在学校舞会上
Before you guys came in to the dance.
在你们闯进来之前
What's her number?
她手机号多少？
She doesn't have a phone.
她没有手机
Her dad doesn't let her, so...
她爸不让她用手机
The only high school girl in America,
我看全美国的高中生
Willa Ferguson, doesn't have a phone.
也就她薇拉·弗格森没有手机了
I guess so.
差不多吧
（营业时间 周一至周六 早9点到晚6点）
Alpha Two, I need a residential address for a Sergio St. Carlos.
二小队 告诉我瑟吉奥·圣卡洛斯的住址
What is it?
那是什么？
It's an old tracking device.
老的追踪配对器
It goes off when it's within 100 yards of hers, if it works.
能用的话只要两个足够近 就会开始放旋律
And it never works.
就没怎么能用过
Sometimes it does, but mostly it doesn't.
有时候确实管用 但基本都不行
What about her phone?
要不打她手机？
She doesn't have a phone.
她没有手机
What, she has a phone?
难道她有手机吗？
Yes.
对啊
She's on... You have her phone number, man?
可她 你有她手机号吗？
No.
没有
Everybody knows she has a phone, though.
不过大家都知道她有手机
Everybody knows she has a...
大家都知道她…
Why didn't she tell me she has a phone?
那她为什么不告诉我？
Maybe she didn't want you to get mad.
也许她不想惹你生气
She's not allowed to have a goddamn phone!
她就不该有手机
Well, maybe she didn't want you to get mad.
她可能就是怕你生气嘛
I don't get mad. I don't get mad about anything anymore.
我不生气 我现在什么事都不生气了
Scared?
害怕吗？
No.
不怕
No?
是吗？
Well, you should be.
你应该害怕
Your dad ever mention Steve Lockjaw?
你爸提过史蒂文·勒喉乔这个人吗？
Yeah.
提过
Yeah? What'd he tell you?
是吗？他怎么说的？
He's the one who killed my mom.
就是他杀了我妈妈
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
Let's fight fire with fire.
上强硬手段 以火制火
Roger that.
遵命
Net call, send in Eddie Van Halen.
全体注意 火爆吉他手出动
【埃迪·范海伦：极具能力的吉他手 此处指具有特殊能力的人员】
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
Personnel ready!
全体就位
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
Gas, gas, gas!
放催泪瓦斯
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
（警察）
Forward, move!
前进 快
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
Oh, my God.
真是倒霉
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
BeeGee!
比吉
（西班牙语）晚上好啊 大师
What's the word?
什么情况？
It's fuckin' World War III out there, yo!
别提了 三战爆发都没这么热闹
（西班牙语）前面乱成一锅粥了
Meet me at Genesis, right now.
马上到新源杂货集合
（西班牙语）没问题 大师
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
They're with me. Okay?
这都是我的人 懂了吗？
Help him bring everything inside,
帮他把东西搬进去
then meet me upstairs.
搬完上楼找我
Don't get locked out!
别被锁外面
（西班牙语）- 你好 我想知道插座在哪儿 - 在那边
Oh! Everybody. The store is closed.
喂 都听好 这里关门了
Help! Go help. Come on.
去帮忙 快点去
You got a charger, homie?
充电的地方在哪儿？
- Let's go, give a hand. - Thank you.
- 都去搭把手 - 谢谢
- Come on. We're closing. - You speak English!
- 关门了 - 你会说英语
Thank you, bro.
谢谢你 哥们
Hey.
是
We got 20 minutes to get everybody to the church.
得在20分钟内把大家送去教堂
- Okay? - Okay.
- 明白吗？ - 明白
- I need your help. Okay? I need you to go upstairs - Okay.
- 我需要你帮忙 你要到楼上去 - 好的
and do me a favor.
帮我做件事儿
I know you don't like the tunnel. You're gonna have to come with me.
你害怕走地道 所以我带你走
- Okay. Okay. - Go upstairs, give 'em a hand. Yeah.
- 好 - 上楼去帮他们吧
Esteban! Esteban, get off your phone. Ándale.
埃斯特班 别玩手机了
Come to the front of the store and keep an eye on the store.
快到大门口去 帮忙盯着点儿
（西班牙语）埃斯特班 快去
Hey, get off the phone!
别玩手机了
Get off the phone! Come on!
别玩手机了 快去
I'm not on the phone, man!
我哪有玩手机 哥们？
（新源杂货）
God damn!
真烦人
- I'm trying to charge the phone! You see that? - Bring it upstairs.
- 我是想给手机充电 懂了吗？ - 拿到楼上去充
- Goddamn, man! - Bring it upstairs.
- 充个电真麻烦 - 到楼上去充
（西班牙语）家人们 家人们
（西班牙语）听我说 赶紧带上孩子 排成一队
（西班牙语）移民局的人就要来了 我们得走了
（西班牙语）快点 快点
（西班牙语）都站成一排 不用担心 不会有事的
（西班牙语）大家都听我说 都不用害怕
（西班牙语）老天会保佑我们的 大家都不会有事
（衣帽大甩卖）
（西班牙语）但我们要赶快离开
Guys, clean it up. Spick-and-span.
东西全都拿走 别留下痕迹
Bob. Not safe for you there. Follow me.
鲍勃 这儿不安全 跟我来
（西班牙语）快点 孩子们 快走
Derrick, line 'em up in the hallway!
德瑞克 让他们在走廊排好队
I'll be in 24!
我去24号房
（西班牙语）没问题 哥们
You win some and you lose some, Bob.
俗话说得好 有得必有失 鲍勃
Yeah.
是啊
Bob, Bob, Bob.
鲍勃 这儿
Get back on defense.
你冷静一点儿
Back on defense, man, yeah.
冷静 没问题
Yeah.
好
Thank you, man. Thank you, thank you.
谢谢兄弟 太谢谢了
Here.
在这儿
Do it in my room. It's more privacy.
到我屋里去 更隐蔽
Aubrey, get off the phones.
奥布里 别玩手机了
Go to the second floor.
赶快到二楼去
We're moving them out.
要转移阵地 别玩了
Where's your room? Back here, man?
你房间在那儿是吗？
- Hey, Bob, Bob. - Yeah?
- 对了 鲍勃 - 什么？
- This is everybody. - Yeah. Hi.
- 认识一下大家 - 好
- Everybody, this is Bob. - Hi.
- 大家认识一下鲍勃 - 嗨
Hello, Bob.
你好 鲍勃
The Gringo Zapata.
他是白人版萨帕塔
【利亚诺·萨帕塔：墨西哥革命领袖】
Everyone, say hello.
都打个招呼
（西班牙语）很好 你好吗 哥们？
（西班牙语）不要认输
Jacob, I need you to go to the second floor.
雅各布 你赶快到二楼去
Marisela, we're moving them out.
玛丽塞拉 要带他们走
- What? - Now, now.
- 什么？ - 赶快去
Yeah. Bob, Bob. Bob. This is Rachel.
好了 鲍勃 这是瑞秋
- Hi, Rachel. How are you? - Rachel, this is Bob
- 嗨 瑞秋 你好吗？ - 这是鲍勃
and this is Landon, the newest one.
这是兰登 最小的一个
Hey, Landon. How are you?
兰登 你好吗？
Hey, is it back there?
嗨 插座在那儿是吗？
- Okay. Yeah. Back here. - Thank you.
- 对 在这儿 - 谢谢
Nice to meet you.
幸会
Right here. Right behind the couch.
就在那个沙发后面
Thank you, brother, thank you.
谢谢你兄弟 谢谢
Mariah. Madison. Come on.
玛利亚 玛迪森 出去
Out.
出去
Come on, it's my room.
别待在我屋里
Thank you, girls.
这才是乖孩子
Yeah. Come on.
好了
Come on. Come on.
拜托 快点
Shit.
倒霉
Sorry, man.
抱歉 兄弟
Come on.
快点儿
It's okay.
没事
Come on, baby. Come on, baby. Come on, baby.
求你了 快点开机
快点开机 快点呀 求你了
I got power. I got power.
开机了 开机了
（西班牙语）那太好了
Come on.
快点
Please, please, please.
快接 快接 快接
"Rise and shine."
“日上三竿”
Hi.
嗨
What's up, homie?
你好 你好兄弟
It's me again. Bob Ferguson.
我又打电话了 我是鲍勃
I don't know if you remember,
还记得吗？
but we spoke earlier on the phone.
我刚才给你打过电话
I think we had a little misunderstanding.
咱俩也许有点小误会
I think we got off on the wrong foot.
也许你对我印象不好
I was trying to get the rendezvous point
我只是想知道集合地点
- for my daughter. Willa. - Right.
- 我想见我女儿 薇拉 - 好吧
If you can't answer "What time is it?"
你回答不出“那现在是几点？”
I cannot give you the rendezvous point.
我就不能告诉你集合地点
- This is a key tenet of the rebellion text. - "What time is it?"
- 这是暗号手册的重要内容 - 几点啊
I'm surprised you can't name it.
你怎么会回答不上来？
I don't know if you are...who you say you are.
抱歉 我怀疑你根本不是鲍勃
Well, look, look, maybe I can...
好吧 要不这样好了
Maybe I can give you some information
我给你一些信息
and then you give me some information, all right?
你也给我一些信息 怎么样？
We'll just share a little bit of information.
互相交换信息
My name is Bob Ferguson.
我是鲍勃·弗格森
I don't know if you've ever heard of me, all right ?
不知道你是否听说过我
I was a part of French 75 for years.
我过去是法式七五的成员
Years and years, all right?
干过很多年
They used to call me "Ghetto Pat,"
大家叫我“穷鬼帕特”
"Rocket Man," something like that.
“火箭男”之类的
Only problem is, I, uh...
唯一的问题是
I fried my brain since then, man.
如今 我的脑子不太好使
I have abused drugs and alcohol
这三十年来我一直嗑药酗酒
for the past 30 years, man.
已经把脑子喝坏了
I'm a drug and alcohol lover
我是个无药可救的酒鬼
and I cannot remember for the life of me,
我只知道 现在我有危险
or the life of my only child,
我唯一的女儿也有危险
the answer to your question, "What time is it?"
可我无论如何也想不起来“那现在是几点？”
8:15.
八点十五
Now, I need this rendezvous point,
听着 我得知道集合地点
you understand what I'm sayin'? I need it.
你懂我的意思吗？告诉我吧
I understand. And the question is...
我懂你的意思 但你要告诉我
- Fuck! - ..."What time is it?"
- 去死吧 - “那现在是几点？”
If you don't give me the rendezvous point,
你要是不告诉我集合地点
I swear to God, I will hunt you down
你就等着瞧吧 我一定会揪出你
and stick a loaded fuckin' hot piece of dynamite
在你五脏六腑里面塞满炸弹
right up your fuckin' asshole.
让你死无葬身之地
Okay, this doesn't feel safe.
好吧 你这话越界了
You're violating my space right now.
侵犯了我的个人空间
Violating your space? Man, come on,
侵犯你的个人空间？
what kind of revolutionary are you, brother?
兄弟 你算什么反抗斗士？
We're not even in the same room here.
我们都不在一个房间
- We're talkin' on the phone, like men! - Rachel, let's take the boys outside...
- 打个电话就侵犯空间了 - 瑞秋 带孩子出去
- Okay, there's no need to shout. - ...to the other room.
- 你没必要大吼大叫 - 去其他屋
This is a violation of my safety.
你在威胁我的生命安全
These are noise triggers.
我感觉很不舒服
Fuckin' noise triggers. Listen,
去你的不舒服 听着
I wanna know somethin'.
我有个问题
I wanna know one thing when this is all said and done.
先不说别的 我只想知道一件事儿
What is your name? I need to know your name.
你叫什么？我想知道你叫什么
My name is...
好吧 我叫…
Comrade Josh.
乔希同志
Yeah. Comrade Josh.
好 乔希同志
Well, get a better name, Comrade Josh.
我劝你换一个名字
That's a fuckin' ridiculous name for a revolutionary, first off.
哪有干革命的现在叫这种名字 太可笑了
Second off,
另外
I wanna know your coordinates.
你现在在哪儿？
I wanna know your location right now.
我要知道你的坐标
What is it?
告诉我
I'm in a secure location, somewhere between
我在一个很安全的地方
the stolen land of the Wabanaki
比东海岸要靠西
【瓦巴纳基与丘马什：北美原住民部族 其领土在殖民扩张中被夺走】
and the stolen land of the Chumash.
比西海岸要靠东 你猜吧
You're fuckin' intolerable, man. You are...
你真是太会恶心人了
【瓦巴纳基：传统领地在今美国东北部与加拿大东部】
You really know... you're really intolerable, man.
你真是把我恶心坏了
This is not the way the revolutionaries do shit.
革命者不应该是这种德行
【丘马什：传统领地在今美国加州南部沿海】
You know how hard you are to talk to?
你一点儿道理都不讲
Do you know the information that I'm trying to give you?
我也要告诉你一句话 知道是什么吗？
You're a little nitpicking prick!
你就是个爱找茬的混蛋
That's what you are, a little nitpicking prick.
没错 你就知道找茬
And you know what I'm gonna do to nitpicking pricks?
知道我会怎么对付你这种人吗？
I'm gonna call in a Greyhawk Ten.
我要召唤灰鹰十号
- You're calling in a Greyhawk Ten? - I'm callin' in a Greyhawk Ten.
- 你要召唤灰鹰十号？ - 没错 灰鹰十号
All right?
明白吗？
I want you to get your supervisor on the phone right now,
立马让你的上级接电话
'cause I know you got one.
我知道你有上级
I know you got one, Comrade Josh. All right?
同志 我要找你的上级聊聊 懂了吗？
Yeah, I'm goin' way over your fuckin' head.
我要直接越过你这个死脑筋
Way over your head.
跟你的上级聊
All right?
懂吗？
Put your commanding officer on the phone now.
马上让你的指挥官接电话
Because you're calling in a Greyhawk Ten?
因为你要召唤灰鹰十号
I'm callin' in
我要召唤
a Greyhawk Ten, Comrade Josh.
灰鹰十号 乔希同志
Please hold.
请稍等
Fuckin' prick. I got him.
死混蛋 没辙了吧
I got him right where I want him.
总算能治治他了
That's some fucked-up, nitpickin' shit, Bob.
这个混蛋听着就很烦人 鲍勃
He got you on one password.
拿着鸡毛当令箭
Assholes.
真恶心
I'm sorry about...
抱歉兄弟
I brought all this shit to your door, man.
我把这些烂事儿带到了这里
I'm sorry about everything.
给你们添麻烦了
（西班牙语）振作起来 鲍勃
We've been laid siege for hundreds of years.
我们已经被围攻几百年了
【几百年：一些地区并入美国后 当地原住民与墨裔长期被排斥】
You did nothing wrong.
你没做错什么
Don't get selfish.
别太自责
Life, man.
生活啊 真是的
Life!
真难
Just always some little... little, tiny detail, right?
总有些破事儿 让你不得安生
（西班牙语）都准备好了 表哥
Okay. Get to the front.
行了 到门口去
Jacob!
雅各布
We go!
要走了
Okay, guys.
好啦
（西班牙语）有秩序地撤离
（西班牙语）走慢一点
（西班牙语）当心一点 我们快走
（西班牙语）晚上好
（西班牙语）我们马上要出发了 好了兄弟 该走了
（西班牙语）很好 非常好
♪ ...saving for just the proper occasion ♪
♪ ...在镜头前亮相 ♪
【歌曲：描述黑人遭受的
压迫和不公 完整版及注释可在
片尾02：37：02欣赏】
♪ Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies and Hooterville Junction ♪
♪ 新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇 ♪
♪ Will no longer be so damn relevant ♪
♪ 上层建筑再也不重要了 ♪
Why is this takin' so long? For God's sakes.
这也太慢了吧
♪ And women will not care if Dick finally got down with Jane ♪
♪ 洗脑的肥皂剧
You guys are so incompetent. For...
你这群人到底行不行啊
♪ On Search for tomorrow ♪
♪ 也洗不掉她们的关切 ♪
Fuck! Hurry up.
可恶 效率低下 快点啊
♪ Because Black people will be in the street ♪
♪ 因为黑人会走上街头 ♪
♪ Looking for a brighter day ♪
♪ 带着未来的希冀 ♪
♪ The revolution will... ♪
♪ 革命永远不会... ♪
Alpha One, this is Zulu.
一小队 这是祖鲁
（警察）
I got a squirter internal to the target building.
目标建筑内有人逃跑
Follow on for Sergio St. Carlos.
追踪瑟吉奥·圣卡洛斯任务需升级行动
I need to go kinetic.
准备使用武力
Setting up breach time now.
准备进行强攻
I need two follow-on vehicles.
开来两辆支援车辆
Yep. Who's this?
喂？是哪位？
Yeah! Hi! Who's this?
喂？嗨 是哪位？
Who's this?
哪位？
- Who's this? - Who's this?
- 你是哪位？ - 你是哪位？
This is Bob Ferguson. Who's this?
我是鲍勃·弗格森 你是谁？
My brother.
好兄弟
Who's this?
你是谁？
It's your man, Talleyrand.
你哥们塔列朗
Talley! Talley, my brother.
塔列 我的好兄弟
My brother, you listen, man. You gotta help me out, man.
兄弟 听我说 我需要你的帮助
They got Willa.
薇拉被带走了
You heard they got Willa, right? I need...
你也知道这事儿吧
I need the rendezvous point, now.
我需要马上知道集合地点
I need you to answer one question for me, Pat.
好 你需要回答一个问题 帕特
No, no, man.
不 不行
Please don't make me go through this, man.
求你别再搞这套了
- I don't remember any more of these answers - Pat. Pat. Slow down. You're gonna know it
- 我已经忘记答案了 - 帕特 冷静 问题很简单
- It's been too many years. Please... - You're gonna know it.
- 过去太多年了 求你别问了 - 你知道答案
What's my favorite kind of pussy?
我最喜欢哪种美女？
Mexican Hairless.
墨西哥靓女 下面剃了毛的
Okay. One second.
好 等一下
You motherfucker. This is a goddamn war hero.
你这个蠢货 他可是大英雄
Hey, rendezvous is Sisters of the Brave Beaver.
集合地点是勇敢海狸修女会
【海狸：象征勤奋与共同营造家园】
【海狸：在英语俚语中亦为女性生殖器的俗称 借用污名化词汇以自我赋权并挑衅权威】
Sisters of the Brave Beaver. I don't know...
勇敢海狸修女会
Is that that compound out in the hills?
是山上的那个吗？
I need the coordinates, exact coordinates.
你得告诉我准确的位置
Okay, one second.
好 等一下
Tell him how to get there.
帮他指路
Apologize. Mean it.
还要道歉 懂吗？
Hello.
喂？
Hi, prick! Give me the fuckin' coordinates now.
嗨 混蛋 快点告诉我准确位置
Okay.
好的
- Make it snappy! - Okay.
- 不要磨蹭 - 好的
Sister Rochelle's
那个修女会
- is located up Old Mission Road... - Old Mission.
- 就在旧传教路.... - 旧传教路
- Okay, slow down, articulate. - ...to Craw Creek Road...
- 行了 慢点儿 说清楚点儿 - 和克劳溪路
（新源杂货）
（警察）
Bring up the hoolie.
上大家伙
Sensei! Sensei!
大师 大师
（西班牙语）边境警察来了 刚破门
（西班牙语）快点 快走 别磨蹭了
（西班牙语）走的时候注意脚下
（西班牙语）老天一定会保佑我们 放心吧
（西班牙语）都快走
- In the Chupacabra Hills. - Chupacabra Hills.
- 在卓柏卡布拉山 - 卓柏卡布拉山
【卓柏卡布拉：拉美民间传说中的“吸羊怪” 象征带有污名化色彩的民俗地区】
And I just wanna formally say that I am sorry.
我想跟你郑重说一声 对不起
- You wanna formally say you're sorry, huh? - Yeah.
- 这时候你知道道歉了 - 是啊
What was the fuckin' password, by the way, you fuckin' prick?
那个问题的答案到底是什么 混蛋？
"Time doesn't exist, yet it controls us anyway."
“时间还不存在 但它仍然控制着我们”
Fuck you, you fuckin' moron!
去死吧 你个死脑筋
Fuck you! You obviously don't have kids, you fuckin' idiot!
去死吧 你这个蠢货肯定没孩子
Hey! Man, I got the coordinates.
兄弟 我知道位置了
It's Old Mission Road to Craw Creek,
先到旧传教路
and then to Chupacabra Hills.
再到克劳溪路 卓柏卡布拉山
【吉姆·克劳：美国历史上代表种族隔离与制度性歧视的代称 此处路名发音接近构成双关】
Time to go, Bob.
该走了 鲍勃
Right, let's go.
好的 走吧
Let's go, I got the coordinates, man.
我知道位置了 走吧
- Look out the window, Bob. - What?
- 鲍勃 小心窗外 - 什么？
Be careful. Look out the window. Be careful.
小心点儿 窗外能看到你
Shit. Shit.
天啊 该死
They're here!
他们来了
God damn it, they're... Shit. They're...
气死我了 真是该死 他们…
O.G., the store is closed. The inquilinos are gone.
奥吉 店关门了“租客”已经都走了
If they knock, you know what to do.
他们要是敲门 你来应付
How'd they find us, man?
我们怎么暴露的？
How'd they find us?
怎么回事？
（西班牙语）快走吧
I think you were making too many calls, man.
你打了太多电话
（西班牙语）走吧
I think they traced your call. They must have traced your calls.
你的信号肯定被追踪了
What's the plan?
现在怎么办？
- What's the plan, man? - BeeGee!
- 有什么计划？ - 比吉
What's the plan?
有什么计划？
I'm thinking.
我正想呢
- Is that my weapon? - Hang on.
- 那是我的武器吗？ - 等等
- BeeGee! Okay. - We gotta go, man.
- 比吉 - 有什么计划？我们得快走
You're gonna take him up on the roof,
听着 你带他到楼顶去
across to my car on Lapham's Alley. Here are my keys.
到拉帕姆巷去找我的车 这是钥匙
You drop him off, you call me.
送完他记得联系我
Latino Heat, come with me!
拉丁小队 走了
No, no, no, man, I'm not goin' with them.
不行 我不跟他们走
No, I'm not goin' with them! I'm supposed to go with you.
我不跟他们走 我应该跟着你
I need you, brother. Please, Sensei.
我需要你 兄弟 帮帮我 大师
Sensei, Sensei, please!
求求你了
Courage, Bob.
鼓起勇气 鲍勃
Courage.
振作起来
That's it?
就这样？
Courage.
振作起来
Yeah. Yeah. Thank you.
也对 好吧 谢谢
Hey! Thank you, Sensei.
谢谢你 大师
Thank you, Sensei! Thank you!
谢谢大师 谢谢
God damn it!
差点忘了
（西班牙语）革命万岁
（西班牙语）万岁
（警察）
This way, Bob!
这边 鲍勃
（西班牙语）来 鲍勃 把东西递给我
Pass me all your shit, man!
把东西都递给我
Here.
给
I don't give a shit what you do.
我不管你用什么办法
I'm gonna need that number in the next ten seconds.
十秒内 你得把号码告诉我
I know nothing, sir.
我真的不知道
Do I look like your parent?
你觉得我像你爸妈那样好糊弄吗？
- Kinda. - Give me the fuckin' number
- 是啊 - 告诉我她的号码
or stand up, put your hands behind your back.
不然就站起来 把手放在背后
- I don't have her phone number. - Up.
- 我不知道她的号码 - 起来
Put your hands behind your back.
把双手放在背后
Cuff him. Get him outta here.
铐上他 把他带走
I have it.
我想起来了
You have it now?
现在你又想起来了
What is it?
是多少？
I thought you took AP Common Sense. Sit the fuck down.
有点常识也知道你没资格讨价还价 坐下吧
What's the number?
号码是多少？
It's under "Hello Kitty."
联系人是“凯蒂猫”
Give it to me.
手机给我
Give it to me!
把手机给我
I asked you if you had a phone.
我刚才问你有手机吗？
You looked me in my face, and you lied.
你看着我的眼睛 说没有
I am here to save your fuckin' life.
我跑来这里是为了救你
Do you understand?
你到底懂不懂？
Don't lie to me again.
不准再骗我了
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
Alpha Two's on the horn!
二小队来报
The female's handset's heading south on 135.
根据手机信号 女目标正沿135号路向南行驶
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
（警察）
Freeze.
等下
Cell One, Exfil.
一组 收队
All right.
好了
（西班牙语）来吧 兄弟们
（西班牙语）能跑多快就跑多快
Fuck.
该死
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
（西班牙语）快点儿 鲍勃 跟上 快点儿
Fuck.
哎呦
（西班牙语）走狗蠢猪
（西班牙语）好了 该走了 我得带上你
（西班牙语）没事的 就这样吧
BeeGee.
比吉
Sensei, your guy fell off the roof and got arrested.
大师 你朋友从屋顶上掉下去 被抓住了
What the fuck happened?
你说什么？
He fell 40 feet and fuckin' fell in a tree, man.
他跳屋顶时撞上树 摔下去十几米
Chota got him with a Taser.
然后被电击枪打中了
And my rifle?
我的步枪呢？
It's with me.
在我这儿
Okay.
好吧
Meet me at Sacred Heart.
圣心教堂集合
（西班牙语）...我们的神在天上
【背景音：出自《圣经·诗篇》第115篇3-5节】
（西班牙语）都随自己的意旨行事
（西班牙语）他们的偶像是金的 银的
（西班牙语）是人手所造的
（因为我饿了 你们给我吃 我做客旅 你们留我住）
（西班牙语）有口却不能言 有眼却不能看
（严禁擅闯 后果自负）
Rochelle.
罗谢尔
Well, Deandra, what new mischief now?
迪安德拉 又惹了什么麻烦？
I have the child Willa Ferguson.
我带来个孩子 薇拉·弗格森
This is Perfidia Beverly Hills' daughter.
她是叛娅·富山的女儿
I'm comin' to you in an hour of need
我来找你 因为我们现在很危险
and desperation for safekeeping.
迫切需要你的帮助
Unbelievable.
真不敢相信
Do I look just like her?
我和我妈长得像吗？
No.
不
Not really.
不是很像
But you do on the inside.
不过你们性格很像
Which makes you quite a risk around here.
对我们来说 你很可能是个祸害
The daughter of a rat
你妈妈是个叛徒
is a baby rat.
你说不定也是
And we must be careful.
我们必须小心一点
Can you cook?
你会做饭吗？
Yes.
会
We will not allow residence to anyone
我们这里有规矩 要想住在这儿
who cannot take responsibility for both
每个人都要承担责任
her input and output.
不能只进不出
I can earn what I eat and secure
放心吧 我会负责好
what I shit, if that's what you mean.
自己的吃喝拉撒
That's what I mean.
你明白就好
Sister Vox,
沃克斯修女
show Baby Perfidia to the Pancho Villa room.
带小叛娅去潘乔·比利亚房
【潘乔·比利亚：墨西哥革命领袖 领导多次武装起义并推动土地再分配】
A'ight.
好的
Let me run shit down to you.
我介绍一下寒舍
So you have the towels over here.
首先 毛巾都在这边
The bathroom is straight through there.
厕所就在那边
The pillows is right there, as you can see.
枕头都在那儿 看到了吗？
And don't ask for the fuckin' Wi-Fi,
别问我无线网络密码是什么
'cause we ain't got none.
这儿没有无线网络
Make yourself at home, Goldilocks.
好好休息吧 大小姐
What does she know?
她知道多少？
She thinks her mom was a hero.
她以为她母亲是英雄
And I...
我有点儿...
I didn't have the guts to tell her the truth.
不忍心告诉她真相
I couldn't.
太残忍了
Perfidia Beverly Hills
叛娅·富山可真行
is a problem that keeps on givin'.
事到如今 还在给我们添麻烦
This revolution doesn't need another one of her runnin' around.
这场革命不能再出第二个叛娅
Shit's hard enough.
本来就够难了
You got more fight in you than the rest of us, Deandra.
迪安德拉 你比我们都要有斗志
I got sick of this shit a long time ago.
这些破事我早就已经受够了
♪ Glory to the newborn king ♪
♪ 荣耀归于新生王 ♪
♪ Hark, the herald angels sing ♪
♪ 听啊 天使高声唱
♪ Glory to the newborn King ♪
♪ 荣耀归于新生王 ♪
♪ Peace on earth and mercy mild ♪
♪ 平安仁慈归世界
♪ God and sinners reconciled ♪
♪ 神与世人再和谐 ♪
♪ Joyful, all ye nations rise ♪
♪ 万国齐起同欢欣
- Tim! - Alice, how are you, darlin'?
- 提姆 - 爱丽丝 你最近好吗？
♪ Join the triumph of the skies ♪
♪ 天上地下共唱和 ♪
Very well. Thank you.
我挺好的 谢谢
You look great. You hungry?
你气色不错 饿了吗？
♪ With angelic hosts proclaim ♪
♪ 同著天军传喜讯
Uh, yeah, yeah. But I'm actually,
是有点儿饿 但没时间吃了
I think I'm about to be runnin' late.
我快要迟到了
♪ Christ is born in Bethlehem ♪
♪ 圣人生在伯利恒 ♪
- Well, I can fix you some pancakes. - Better get down there.
- 这样吧 我给你做薄烤饼 - 我得赶紧过去
You could have 'em on your way out.
你可以拿着路上吃
♪ Hark, the herald angels sing ♪
♪ 听啊 天使高声唱
Are these the banana pancakes?
你要做香蕉薄烤饼吗？
The famous Alice banana pancakes?
大家都说你做的很好吃
♪ Glory to the newborn king ♪
♪ 荣耀归于新生王 ♪
Those are the ones.
没错 你猜对啦
I know they're waiting for you.
我知道他们在等你
I better get down there.
我得赶紧过去
It's great to see you again, Alice.
见到你很高兴 爱丽丝
♪ Hail the Heav'n-born Prince of Peace ♪
♪ 欢迎天降和平王
Oh, good to see you, Tim.
我也很高兴 提姆
♪ Hail the Sun of Righteousness ♪
♪ 欢迎辉煌公义光 ♪
♪ Light and life to all he brings ♪
♪ 赐生命也赐光
♪ Risen with healing in his wings ♪
♪ 医治世人照万方 ♪
♪ Mild he lays his glory by ♪
♪ 弃荣华甘虚己
♪ Born that man no more may die ♪
♪ 降生救人免死亡 ♪
♪ Born to raise the sons of earth ♪
♪ 降生使人得高升
♪ Born to give them second birth ♪
♪ 降生使人得重生 ♪
♪ Hark, the herald angels sing ♪
♪ 听啊 天使高声唱
♪ Glory to the newborn King ♪
♪ 荣耀归于新生王 ♪
Come in.
请进
Tim.
提姆
Merry Christmas. Hail Saint Nick.
共荣圣诞 向圣尼古拉敬礼
【圣尼古拉：基督教圣徒 圣诞老人原型】
Merry Christmas.
共荣圣诞
- How ya doin'? - Good, good.
- 你最近好吗？ - 挺好的
It's been too long.
好久不见
Yeah, it's good to see you again, Sandy.
是啊 终于又见面了 桑迪
You know Virgil Throckmorton.
你认识维道尔·司空伯顿吧？
Virgil's down from Cleansing and Distortion.
净化与纠偏部的
Merry Christmas.
共荣圣诞
- And you know Bill Desmond from Whitehall. - Yes.
- 白厅的比尔·戴斯蒙你也认识 - 是啊
Bill, good to see you again, and merry Christmas.
比尔 再次见面很高兴 共荣圣诞
And of course you know Roy More.
你也认识罗伊·摩尔
Fifth Fleet Field General from the Southwest.
西南军区第五舰队战地司令
Absolutely, sir. Good morning.
当然认识 早上好
Take a seat.
坐下吧
So...
所以
what's cookin'?
是怎么了？
How can I help?
要我做什么？
Well, Tim,
是这样的 提姆
There's this troubling little rumor we've just heard.
我们听到一个很可怕的传言
And we brought you in
找你过来
to see if you can help clear it up.
是希望你能帮忙理清一些事
I'm gonna hand you over to Bill. He'll give you the details.
比尔会向你具体交代
- Over to you, Bill. - All right.
- 交给你了 比尔 - 好的
Tim, I'm gonna get right to it. Um...
提姆 我就直说了
There's an unconfirmed report
我接到一份报告说
that Colonel Steven J. Lockjaw
史蒂文·勒喉乔上校
is the father of a mixed-race child.
其实有个混血的私生子
Which mix?
混了哪个人种？
There's no real easy way to say this, but...
我真的难以启齿 但是
Yeah.
好吧
It's Black.
是黑的
Well, uh...
天啊
That would be quite the revelation
这件事如果是真的
if it were true.
那就太可怕了
Bill, may I ask what your source is?
比尔 请问这消息哪儿来的？
Sure. That's part of a Double Yankee White background check.
来自纯血美国白人背景审查报告
Some old paperwork turned up in a computer file
我们在电脑里找到了一些旧文件
on the Black militant named Junglepussy.
是关于一个叫贱女姜戈的黑人罪犯
She told an officer this very story 15 years ago.
15年前 她就跟一个警官讲过这件事
Fifteen years ago.
15年前啊
It's been there the whole time, in ancient file. Pure luck we caught it.
那些文件一直都在 我们能翻出来纯属走运
So where's the Pussy?
这个贱女在哪儿？
Oh, she's long dead.
她早就死了
Oh. No more Pussy.
哦 贱命一条
Now, a few days ago,
总之 几天前
Lockjaw hired a bounty hunter
勒喉乔雇佣赏金猎人
to make a civilian extraction in El Paso.
在埃尔帕索抓走了一个平民
It was led by an Avanti Q. You know him?
带队的是阿威腾·魁 你认识吗？
Yeah, I know Avanti. He's a good soldier.
认识 阿威腾是个好军人
Not great?
有多好？
I mean, he's excellent, but he's not a native son.
很不错 可惜他不是白人
That's his dirty little secret.
这是他的肮脏小秘密
He passes for half-Mexican, but he's actually part Comanche
他假装是半个墨西哥人 其实有印第安血统
or, I don't know, Eskimo.
还是爱斯基摩人血统
He's a fantastic tracker.
他很擅长追踪
He'll tell you how much money someone had in their pocket based on a footprint,
光看脚印 他就知道对方口袋里有多少钱
but he is not homegrown, so I would not trust it.
但他不是白人 所以不可信
Yeah, well, he's apparently good enough
不过 显然他有足够的本事
to find what Lockjaw was lookin' for.
找到勒喉乔一直想找的人
Yeah. He found Howard Sommerville.
没错 他找到了霍华德·萨默威尔
Ex-French 75. He runs an underground railroad,
前法式七五成员 现在运营一个地下组织
bringing illegals from our southern border
将非法移民从南方边境
to Baktan Cross in the north,
带去北方的归援十字市
where he set up a so-called sanctuary city,
把那儿变成了庇护城市
giving jobs and housing to drug dealers and psychopaths.
帮助毒贩和神经病在美国扎根
He's also a reefer addict.
他还是一个瘾君子
Really? Well, he sounds like a class act, this guy.
真的？这么说他还挺有能耐的
Next thing we know,
抓走他之后
Colonel Lockjaw's mobilized his task force into Baktan Cross
勒喉乔上校的特遣队 进入了归援十字市
and conducted a Class-A raid
对香香鸡速冻食品厂
on the Chicken Lickin' Frozen Farm.
进行了最高等级突袭
Oh, no. I love their nuggets.
哦不 我很喜欢他们家的鸡块
Well, this could mean a nugget shortage.
是吗？暂时可能买不到了
Not to mention the Chicken Lickin's owned by our fellow Christmas Adventurer,
更何况 厂长也是我们俱乐部的成员
Brother Burt Rimhorn, who wants his wetbacks back to work.
他希望那些拉丁狗非法劳工 能快点复工
Next...
接着说
He hit the high school, Tim.
他还搜查了高中 提姆
Yeah.
没错
The high school.
是那所高中
And now, all hell's broken loose on the streets of Baktan Cross.
现在归援十字市已经乱成一锅粥了
And he's turned off his A-TAK's.
他还关闭了实时共享
I'm sorry to interrupt,
抱歉 我插一下嘴
But I think I'm pickin' up what you gents are layin' down here.
我听明白你们想说什么了
This is a curious chain of events.
这些事儿确实不寻常
So Lockjaw's lookin' for his half-breed,
勒喉乔在找自己的杂种私生子
but do we know where the mama bear is?
但护崽的妈妈在哪里？
Funny you should ask that.
这事情可有意思了
Perfidia Beverly Hills.
母亲叛娅·富山
Currently M.I.A. Former French 75.
目前下落不明 前法式七五成员
She went into witness protection about 15 years ago,
15年前做了污点证人
only to disappear.
后来就消失了
The arresting agent...
逮捕她的警官
Colonel Steven J. Lockjaw.
正是史蒂文·勒喉乔上校
Agency sightings have her in Cuba or Algiers,
有些报告说她在古巴
depending on the report.
也有人说她在阿尔及尔
So...not the mothering type, I take it.
看来 她没有母爱
And they call us the savages.
他们还好意思说我们野蛮
Lockjaw got his dick dirty.
勒喉乔把自己染脏了
He needs to clean it.
他正在清洗自己
If he can find this kid,
如果他能找到孩子
He can dispose of the evidence,
他就能消灭证据
And continue to make fools out of all of us.
继续把我们耍得团团转
What would you like me to do, sir?
您希望我做什么？
Tim, given your expertise in family cases,
提姆 你很擅长解决家庭案件
we felt that maybe--
我们希望你...
Make it clean.
处理干净
Clean?
干净？
We should all be able to eat off the floor.
要干净到地板都能当镜子
Yeah. It's that clean.
对 要不留痕迹
Yes, sir.
遵命
Well, all right, gents. Looks like I'm headed west.
好了 先生们 我该去西部了
And may Saint Nick be with you.
愿圣尼古拉保佑你
All hail Saint Nick.
向圣尼古拉敬礼
I have something to ask you, okay?
我能问你一件事吗？
'Kay.
问吧
Was she a rat?
她是叛徒吗？
Yeah, she was.
对 她是
My dad told me she was a hero.
我爸爸说她是个英雄
Hey, stop banging your head. Stop banging your head.
不要撞脑袋 不要撞脑袋
Stop banging your head on that.
不要再撞脑袋了
Okay.
好吧
Sir, do you know your last name?
先生 你姓什么？
No.
不知道
What's your last name?
你叫什么？
Batman.
蝙蝠侠
Okay, come on. I need to know your real last name.
别闹了 赶紧说实话
Um, Parker. Peter Parker, man.
帕克 彼得·帕克
【彼得·帕克：虚构人物 蜘蛛侠本名】
Peter Parker.
彼得·帕克
- Yeah. - All right, listen. This is your last chance. If you don't give me your real last name,
- 对 - 听着 你不想罪名加重的话
- it's gonna be another charge. What is it? - Okay, okay.
- 最好乖乖说实话 - 好好好
Stop harassing me, for God sakes!
别再念叨了 烦死了
Parker. Jim Parker, man.
帕克 我叫吉姆·帕克
Your name's Jim Parker?
你叫吉姆·帕克？
Yeah.
对
Okay, Jim. What's your date of birth?
好 吉姆 你的出生日期
I'm somewhere in the '80s, man.
大概是一九八几年
In the '80s.
八零后
Yeah.
对
Let's go. You're up.
该走了 到你了
Let's go.
该走了
Get up. Well, fuck.
起来 老实点儿
Sit down there.
坐下
Mr. Jim Parker, is that correct?
你是吉姆·帕克先生吗？
Forty-two years old?
42岁
Sir, she's gonna be taking your vitals behind you, okay?
她要从身后测量你的生命体征
Mr. Parker.
帕克先生
Mr. Parker, over here.
请看这儿 先生
Do you have any medical problems?
你有既往病史吗？
Yeah.
有
Mr. Parker, can you look at me, sir?
帕克先生 请看着我
Bob. Can you look at me?
鲍勃 能看着我吗？
Are you diabetic?
你有糖尿病吗？
有糖尿病吗？
Uh-huh.
嗯
Yeah.
是吗？
Did you take your insulin yesterday?
你昨天打胰岛素了吗？
You know, if you're a bad hombre,
你要是有糖尿病
You make sure you take your insulin on a daily basis. Right?
必须每天都打胰岛素 知道吗？
Officer, we're not gonna be able to take this one. He needs to go out to the ER.
警官 这里检查不了 他得去急救室
Thank you, sir. Have a good day.
谢谢配合 再见
Hey, how's it goin'?
嗨 你好吗？
- Good. How are you? - Good, thanks.
- 挺好的 你呢？ - 也挺好
Mr. Parker, here's your restroom, okay?
帕克先生 这边是卫生间
Let's check your sugar.
来查查血糖
You are gonna go through the bathroom,
穿过卫生间就是走廊
straight down the hall to the right to the fire escape.
走到头 再右转 就是逃生梯
Right now.
现在就走
Right now?
现在？
Right now.
现在
♪ Ready, get ready ♪
♪ 赶快 准备好 ♪
Hey, Officer. You wanna come sign this intake form with me?
警官 请帮我签一下住院表格
♪ Ready or not, here I come ♪
♪ 有没有准备好 我都要来了
♪ You can't hide ♪
♪ 你无处可逃 ♪
♪ Gonna find you ♪
♪ 我会找到你
♪ And keep you happy ♪
♪ 用幸福包围你 ♪
♪ Ready or not, here I come ♪
♪ 有没有准备好 我都要来了
God!
倒霉
♪ You can't hide ♪
♪ 你无处可逃 ♪
♪ Gonna love you ♪
♪ 我要爱着你
Hey, Bob!
嘿 鲍勃
♪ And make you love me ♪
♪ 让你也爱上我 ♪
Sensei, man! Sensei, brother! Oh, my God.
大师 我的兄弟 天啊
Sensei, thank you.
大师 太谢谢你了
♪ You can't run away ♪
♪ 你别想逃避
Thank you, brother. Thank you!
谢谢你兄弟 太感谢你了
- Thank you! - Hey. Here, have one.
- 谢谢你 谢谢 - 来喝点儿 好啦
♪ From this love I got, oh baby ♪
♪ 逃不掉我的爱 宝贝
Oh, my God.
老天啊
All right. Let's do a selfie.
好了 一起拍张照
♪ Hey baby, 'cause I got a lot, yeah ♪
♪ 宝贝 因为我有很多爱 ♪
Oh, my God, you got... you got a what?
我的天啊 真是 什么？
Okay. we did it. We did it.
好的 成功了 逃出来了
♪ Anywhere you go ♪
♪ 无论你去哪里
- Let's get out of here, man. - Where we goin'?
- 咱们赶紧走吧 赶紧走 - 要去哪儿？
♪ My poor heart's gotta know, oh baby ♪
♪ 我的心都会找到你 ♪
Sisters of the Brave Beaver. Chupacabra Hills.
勇敢海狸修女会 卓柏卡布拉山
- Chupacabra Hills. - Let's play offense.
- 卓柏卡布拉山 - 开始行动
♪ Hey baby, you can't hide from my love, no ♪
♪ 你无法躲藏我的爱 ♪
Siri, Sisters of the Brave Beaver.
导航 勇敢海狸修女会
Getting directions to the Sisters...
正在导航 勇敢海狸修女会
Chupacabra Hills.
卓柏卡布拉山
♪ Ready or not, here I come ♪
♪ 有没有准备好 我都要来了 ♪
Okay. Not every day you get to rescue a 75er
好了 我居然救了法式七五的成员
♪ Gonna find you ♪
♪ 我会找到你
Twice in the same day!
还一天救了两次
Let's rock and fuckin' roll!
走吧 开始行动
♪ And keep you happy ♪
♪ 用幸福包围你 ♪
Yeah!
好
Let's go!
出发
（当心孩童）
（格蕾西路口）
（商店）
♪ Ready or not ♪
♪ 有没有准备好
♪ Here I come ♪
♪ 我都要来了
♪ You can't hide ♪
♪ 你无处可逃 ♪
♪ Gonna love you ♪
♪ 我要爱着你
♪ And make you love me ♪
♪ 让你也爱上我 ♪
Any more?
还有吗？
No, sir. He's right here.
没有了 他在这儿
♪ Anywhere you go ♪
♪ 无论你去哪里
Buddha bean.
墨西哥胖子
♪ My poor heart's gotta know, oh baby ♪
♪ 我的心都会找到你 ♪
Sir, I'm Colonel Steve Lockjaw.
我是史蒂文·勒喉乔上校
♪ Hey baby, you can't hide from my love, no ♪
♪ 你无法躲藏我的爱 ♪
I'm not to be fucked with.
你最好别耍我
You got information for me, spit it out.
你有什么线索 快点说
I saw a car, a gray van heading north, up Craw Creek Road.
我看到一辆灰色面包车 沿克劳溪路向北走
Carrying?
车上有谁？
Couldn't tell.
看不清楚
White man driving, Black girl passenger.
开车的是白人 带着个黑人女孩
♪ Ready, get ready ♪
♪ 赶快 准备好 ♪
North. What's in these hills?
北边 山里有什么？
♪ Ready, get ready ♪
♪ 赶快 准备好 ♪
Sisters of the Brave Beaver.
勇敢海狸修女会
Who are they?
里面有谁？
（警察）
They grow weed. They're nuns.
一群修女 种大麻的
♪ Ready or not ♪
♪ 有没有准备好
Is that some kind of sick joke on God?
什么？你在拿上帝开低俗玩笑吗？
♪ Here I come ♪
♪ 我都要来了
♪ You can't hide ♪
♪ 你无处可逃 ♪
I'm not joking.
我是说真的
♪ Gonna find you ♪
♪ 我会找到你
How many women?
有多少修女？
I don't know. A bunch. Ten or 20.
我也不清楚 十几二十个吧
♪ And keep you happy ♪
♪ 用幸福包围你 ♪
♪ You better come on, baby ♪
♪ 你最好接受 宝贝 ♪
Weapons?
有武器吗？
I think they're vegetarian.
她们应该不杀生
♪ Okay okay... ♪
♪ 你逃不掉的... ♪
Men, let's do what we do.
都听着 使命召唤 准备行动
Delta-Two, this is Delta-One.
二组 这里是一组
We need to pull imagery.
请侦查
Mountain chain, ten kilometers northwest. How copy?
西北十公里处的山脉 收到
Hands, hands, hands!
举起手来
（警察）
（人类联盟野战行动 边境战术应对小组）
Dismissed.
解散
Come closer.
过来
（现场亲子鉴定仪）
If this doesn't line up, you'll go free.
如果不匹配的话 我就放你走
But if it does line up...
但如果匹配的话
if this is a straight line...
如果连成横线
（现场亲子鉴定仪）
you got a problem.
你就有麻烦了
What is it?
这是什么？
It's your future.
你的未来
（现场亲子鉴定仪）
How old are you now?
你今年多大？
You're 16 or 17. It's either one of those.
你不是十六岁 就是十七岁
You have a boyfriend?
有男朋友吗？
I don't have anything to say to you.
我不想和你说话
You're too young to have a boyfriend, so the answer's no.
你这么小 肯定没有男朋友
Don't answer for me.
不要替我回答
It all makes sense.
这下我懂了
You snag her out of the high school.
你把她从高中救走
Find her phone.
找到她的手机
Curb stomp that.
并毁掉了它
But then you fumble her on the 90-yard line
眼看就要没事了 却在这个破修道院
at some stank-ass nunnery? Mm!
被我们抓到了
That's gotta hurt.
真是遗憾啊
You help me, I'll help you.
你帮我的话 我就会帮你
You give me Pat Calhoun...
告诉我上哪儿找帕特·卡尔霍恩
The Rocket Man, Ghetto Pat...
也叫“火箭男”和“穷鬼帕特”
And I'll let you go home, and I'll let you save that little girl.
我就送你回家 去救那女孩
You know she's with the Colonel, right?
她现在就在上校那儿
By "home"...
忘说了
I do mean federal prison for you.
送你回家就是回监狱
Did you rape her?
你强奸了她吗？
Do you think you're my daughter?
你觉得我们是父女吗？
Did you love her?
你爱她吗？
Answer me! Do you think you're my daughter?
回答我 你觉得我们是父女吗？
It doesn't matter what that test says.
测试结果不重要
I have a father, and it's not you.
我有爸爸 可不是你
Is that what you call a father? He wasn't enough for your mother.
得了吧 你妈都觉得那人能力不行
How's he gonna be enough for you?
你又怎么会崇拜他呢？
（现场亲子鉴定仪）
Where is he?
他在哪儿？
I swear, I don't know. I don't know.
我可以对天发誓 我不知道
Deandra, you know how many people sit across
迪安德拉 这种话我听过太多次了
from me and swear to God...
耳朵都快起茧了
They don't know?
你们都爱说
"I swear to God, I don't know."
“我发誓我不知道”
I swear to God if you do know,
我也发誓 如果你知道
We can save that girl.
就能救那个女孩
The girl didn't do anything, and I don't know.
那女孩是无辜的
I don't know where he is.
我真不知道帕特在哪儿
If I knew where he was, I would tell you.
我要是知道就说了
I don't know where he is.
但我真不知道
What the fuck's wrong with you?
你怎么回事？
Where is he?
告诉我帕特在哪儿
Save yourself, go to prison,
你就能活着去坐牢
I'll take it to the Colonel,
我带着消息去找上校
You save the girl.
那女孩就能得救
Those are your options. You're in a lose-lose,
棋局已定 你无路可选了
maybe-save-your-life position.
就看你想不想保住小命了
You should put on more makeup to make yourself look better.
你应该多化化妆 让自己好看点儿
You go to a dance,
舞会这样重要的场合
you make an effort.
不能犯懒
You put on more makeup.
必须好好化妆
Why is your shirt so tight?
你的衬衫怎么那么紧？
I'm not gay, if that's what you're sayin'.
你不要乱猜 我可不是基佬
I didn't say that.
我可没这么说
I'm not a homosexual.
反正我不是同性恋
I did not say that,
这是你提的
But I see the lifts in your shoes.
但我确实发现你穿了增高鞋垫
Oh, you are a smartass.
你以为自己很聪明吗？
You... Oh, yeah, yeah.
真是太典型了
You just, you're just a little princess, aren't you?
你就是个娇生惯养的小公主
Smart mouth. Like your mother.
就会耍嘴皮子
Your mother had a smart mouth, and I buried her.
你妈嘴巴也很毒 最后还是被我征服了
Are you having trouble remembering what you just read?
真聪明 又要看说明书 刚说过就忘了吗？
If it's a straight line, I have a problem.
如果连成横线 我就有麻烦了
If it's not, you have to let me go.
如果不是 就放我走
God, there's no way I'm actually yours,
你不可能是我爸爸
'cause I can actually fucking read.
因为我没这么笨
You shut up. Just shut up!
够了 闭上你的臭嘴
You fucking mutt!
你就是个小杂种
Uh-oh.
坏了
Get my vehicle. Put my kid in the car.
把我车开来 箱子放上面
Just never thought this fucker would come back for us, you know?
我从没想过这混蛋还会回来抓我们
I got lazy, man. I wasn't payin' attention.
是我大意了 没有好好防范
I thought the person comin' through that door one day
我没想过这混蛋会回来
was gonna be her mom, not this fuckin' asshole.
倒是想过她妈叛娅可能会回来
See her daughter, you know, she'd teach her girl stuff,
我以为她会回来看女儿 教她一些女孩的事儿
She'd do her hair, she'd...
给她扎个头发
Be a mom.
做回妈妈
I can't do her hair, man.
我不懂怎么帮她扎头发
You know that?
你知道吗？
I don't know how to do her hair right.
我怎么也扎不好
Well...
是吗？
Don't go dark on me, Bob.
别太伤感了 鲍勃
I won't.
好吧
I'm here. I'm here.
好了 没事了
Bring it down, bro.
把酒收起来 兄弟
【车内喝酒：美国大多数州禁止驾驶员和乘客 在车内打开或饮用酒精饮料容器】
Motherfucker.
真是倒霉
Here he comes.
麻烦来了
Put this in your backpack.
把这藏你包里
Guess this is the end of the line, huh?
看来咱们完蛋了 是吧？
Not for you.
你还没完
Ocean waves. Ocean waves.
心如止水 平静 平静
I gotta ditch you, Kemosabe.
我得让你下车了 好兄弟
- What? - You gotta hit it on foot.
- 什么？ - 你必须走过去
On foot?
走过去？
Yeah.
对
Here we go.
听我说
I'm gonna turn at this gas station,
我会在前面加油站转弯
I'm gonna slow down,
然后降低车速
and you tuck and roll.
你跳下车
I'll take it from there.
剩下交给我
Unbuckle and get ready.
解开安全带 准备好
- Tuck and roll. - Yeah.
- 跳下车 - 对
Okay.
好
You know what freedom is?
知道自由本质是什么吗？
What?
是什么？
No fear.
就是不害怕
Just like...
就像是...
Tom fuckin' Cruise.
酷毙的阿汤哥那样
【阿汤哥：汤姆·克鲁斯好莱坞动作巨星 以高风险亲自完成特技闻名】
Okay. Jump on four. One...
听我数到四就跳 一
...two...
二
Give me the gun!
把枪给我
...three...
三
Go!
跳
Four!
四
Slow down!
慢点儿
Go!
跳啊
Four, Bob!
跳啊 鲍勃
Go, four!
快点儿跳
Get up! We're leaving.
起来 得走了
Making up for lost time?
你怨我没有陪过你
Little daddy-daughter games?
想让我陪你玩游戏
Daddy-daughter games?
玩警察抓小偷是吗?
I am a Christmas Adventurer!
我可是圣诞先驱
Do you know what that is?
知道那意味着什么吗？
No!
放开我
I have a higher calling.
我有更崇高的使命
It is a higher honor
跟我的使命相比
than having you.
你的小命根本不算什么
Contact, contact! 12 o'clock!
遇敌 遇敌 十二点钟方向
I loved her, in case you were wonderin'.
老实说 我爱过她
Best goddamn-looking
你妈是我这辈子见过的
witch I ever saw.
最漂亮的黑妞
Shut up.
住嘴
Yeah, she was possessed.
可惜 那时她着魔了
- Shut the fuck up. - She was insane.
- 闭上你的臭嘴 - 是个激进的疯子
Like you. You have it in you.
很像你 你跟她一模一样
I smelled it from within her, and I can smell it from within you.
她身上有疯子的味儿 你身上也有
She was a fucking rat.
她是个该死的叛徒
She was a warrior,
她是个战士
A righteous warrior of freedom!
一心一意为了自由而战
And she fought the weak!
她碾压所有的弱者
She was a fucking rat!
她是个该死的叛徒
You should respect your mother and your father both.
你应该学会尊重自己的父母
Poke your fuckin' eyes out.
我真该好好教教你
Avanti.
阿威腾
How's the bounty business?
最近生意怎么样？
It's all right. How's it with you?
还行吧 你最近怎样？
Things could be better.
说不上很理想
It's not one thing, it's a-fuckin'-nother.
麻烦一桩接一桩
Do you find that to be true?
能理解这种感觉吗？
Anyway...
总之
I need to dispose of this one.
我得处理掉这个麻烦
Who is it?
是谁？
Murder suspect. Wetback half-breed.
杀人嫌犯 拉丁狗混血
Involved in narco cartels. Nobody that will be missed.
干过非法贸易 死了也没人在乎
That's a kid. I don't do kids.
不行 我不杀小孩
Kids do bad shit.
小孩也会犯罪
Why don't you do it?
你干吗不自己动手？
I can't do it. I'm busy. So who can do it?
我没时间 得找人替我
Well, get Erik Garrow to do it.
你可以找埃里克·割罗
I don't want Erik Garrow to do it.
我不想找埃里克·割罗
I'll pay you double your daily rate, get this done.
干掉她 我付你双倍酬劳
I don't give a shit. I'm not doin' it.
那也不行 我不干
All right.
好吧
You know the 1776,
知道一七七六吗？
about five miles outside Del Rio by Walter's Landing?
离德尔里奥有8公里 靠近沃特兰
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- 知道 - 好
You get her to them, I'll pay you your daily rate.
把她送过去 每天多少钱按定好的给你
Smart aleck.
耍小聪明
You got no manners, God damn it!
死丫头 一点儿规矩都不知道
You weren't raised right!
没家教的玩意儿
You see that?! You see that?!
看到了吗？看见没有？
That's what your mother brought up.
你妈就这么教你的
Get... there.
进去
Kick all the way.
很好 小兔崽子
Yeah, go ahead, kick! Kick, kick!
你就闹吧 再大点儿劲
I'm sorry it had to end this way.
我也不想做得这么绝
If you had any manners, we might have gotten to know each other.
你要是听话 咱俩还能聊聊
Little bitch child.
小兔崽子
Bitch child.
真该死
All goddamn witches...
跟她妈一样的坏黑妞
Where the fuck are you taking me, asshole?
死混蛋 你想带我去什么地方？
Someone gonna come by lookin' for you?
会有人过来找你吗？
I said, is someone gonna come by lookin' for you?
问你呢 会有人来找你吗？
Yeah.
当然
They're gonna find me,
他们会来救我
and they're gonna fuck you up.
把你大卸八块
（迪乔治乔路）
Fuck, fuck, fuck. Come on.
该死 他们到底去哪儿了？
Fuck!
可恶
去哪儿了？
（新鲜水果）
（西班牙语）你们好
（西班牙语）你好 兄弟
（西班牙语）你们有没有看到
（西班牙语）一辆黑色SUV？
（西班牙语）上面坐着一个非常年轻的女孩
（西班牙语）还有个看着很坏很坏的男人
（新鲜水果）
（西班牙语）往那边开了
（西班牙语）- 那边？ - 那边
（西班牙语）不是那边吗？
（西班牙语）那边 往右拐
（西班牙语）谢谢你们 谢谢
Head.
低头
All right, lift your shirt and turn around.
提起外套 转身
Put your hands on top of your head.
把手举过头顶
All right, let's go to work.
快点搜吧
Do not move. Do you have any weapons on you, sir?
不要动 你有带武器吗？
No, sir.
没有 警官
Why are you running from us?
你为什么要逃跑？
Had a long day, ma'am.
我累糊涂了 警官
You didn't see the lights back there?
你没看到警灯吗？
Yes, I did.
看到了
What did you toss out of the vehicle?
你往车外扔了什么？
'Scuse me?
什么？
What did you toss out of the vehicle back there?
你刚才往车外扔了什么？
Trash.
垃圾
You sure about that?
你确定吗？
Yes, ma'am.
确定 警官
You been drinking today?
你今天喝酒了？
I've had a few.
喝了一点儿
A few what?
一点是多少？
Few small beers.
就喝了点小啤酒
【酒类法律：美国大多数州酒驾将罚款 吊照 严重或累犯可拘留起诉】
（警惕山洪）
There you are.
找到了
I see you.
看到你了
终于找到了
I got you,
找到你了
motherfucker, I got you.
混蛋 等着瞧吧
Faster, you fuckin' piece of shit!
破车 别慢腾腾的
Go!
快点儿
Who's this asshole?
哪冒出的混蛋
What do you want?
你想干吗？
（残酷无情）
Is that from Lockjaw?
是勒喉乔送来的吗？
We got a body.
来处理尸体
Copy, copy.
收到 收到
Thanks, wagon-burner.
谢啦 印第安佬
Fuck.
该死
可恶
Oh, no.
不是吧
No, no, no, no, no, no.
不 不 不
God damn it.
可恶
Fuck.
该死
Fuck!
可恶
（残酷无情）
Hey, fuckstick, what are ya doin'?
嘿 蠢货 你要干吗？
Hey, Red, I know you hear me.
傻土著 别装聋子
（售卖冰块 梅里克商行 爱计较者出门左转不送）
【ICE：美国移民和海关执法局同样缩写为ICE 负责美国境内移民和海关执法任务】
That firewater's got you fuckin' retarded.
酒喝多了 脑子喝残了？
Oh, God.
天啊
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!
Green..."
“新青...”
Willa!
薇拉
Fuck.
可恶
Please, please.
转过去 转过去
Okay. Okay.
好了 好了
Fuck!
该死
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!"
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
What?!
什么？
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!"
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
I don't know--
我不知道
Say it!
快说
Willa?
薇拉
Willa!
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!"
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
No, no, no, baby, it's me.
不 不 宝贝 是我
Willa, it's...
薇拉 是我
"Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies, and Hooterville Junction!"
“新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇”
Okay!
好的
好
It's your dad, Willa!
爸爸来了 薇拉
"Will no longer be so goddamn relevant."
“上层建筑再也不重要了”
Look at me.
看看我
Who are you?
你这白男是谁？
It's your dad!
我是你爸爸
Look at me.
仔细看
It's okay.
没事了
没事
Are you okay?
没受伤吧 宝贝？
你没事吧？伤着了吗？
Are you okay?
都还好吧？
Come on. Go to the car. Go!
好了 快上车 快点儿
Let's go. Let's go.
走吧 我们走
♪ （西班牙语）孤独
Oh, my God.
太可怕了
♪ （西班牙语）让我在焦虑中颤抖 ♪
You're okay now. You're okay.
已经没事儿了 放心吧
♪ （西班牙语）每个人
♪ （西班牙语）都对我不闻不问 ♪
♪ （西班牙语）女人
♪ （西班牙语）你可问问上天
♪ （西班牙语）是否曾有一刻
♪ （西班牙语）我对你爱意消减 ♪
♪ （西班牙语）大海
♪ （西班牙语）映出我的内心
♪ （西班牙语）深知我曾几度哭泣
♪ （西班牙语）只因你无情背叛 ♪
Do you know a Black militant by the name of
你认识黑人激进分子
Perfidia Beverly Hills?
叛娅·富山吗？
Yes, I do.
认识
And was she a member of the rebel group known as the French 75?
她难道不是反动组织法式七五的成员吗？
She was.
是的
Yeah.
噢
Colonel Lockjaw...
勒喉乔上校
did you engage in a romantic relationship with this woman?
你是不是和她 有过不正当的男女关系？
♪ （西班牙语）可是你
♪ （西班牙语）谁知道你身在何处
Gentlemen...
先生们
I have engaged the enemy face-to-face in battle.
我曾在战场上与敌人正面厮杀
And in the dark alleys and shadows of espionage.
也曾在阴暗角落跟间谍斗智斗勇
I was once...
我曾经被
raped in reverse.
逆向强奸过
Raped in reverse?
逆向强奸？
Could you explain how that might...
能请你解释一下
work for us, Colonel Lockjaw?
那是什么意思吗？
The enemy employed deception. I was drugged.
我不小心被敌军骗了 被下了药
And while unconscious...
我失去了意识
My brain was not working.
大脑无法正常工作
But my power was, and I believe it was taken advantage of.
但我的雄风仍在 所以被敌军占了便宜
What kind of proof do you have?
你有证据吗？
If you were unconscious, how do you know this to be true?
如果没有意识 你怎么知道的？
I don't know it to be true, but I suspect it.
我是推测出来的
When I awoke, there was sensitivity in a private place,
我醒来后 觉得那里有点儿不舒服
and there was some residue of an interaction.
还发现了那种事的痕迹
Interaction?
那种事？
I believe she was a sperm thief.
她偷了我的生命之源
A semen demon.
偷精生子
That's correct.
没错
Colonel Lockjaw,
勒喉乔上校
What would be the purpose of the enemy raping you in reverse?
敌军为什么要大费周章逆向强奸 怀你的孩子？
They saw the power of my mind and body.
我的心智与体魄充满了威能
They desired it.
他们馋得不行
Congratulations, Steve.
祝贺你 史蒂文
You're a Christmas Adventurer.
你成功加入了圣诞先驱俱乐部
Oh, Mommy. Thank you, sir.
妈呀 谢谢您 先生
Let me show you around southwest headquarters.
我带你参观一下西南总部
Sure.
好啊
Should we go for a walk?
我们走吧
Yes, sir.
好的
First stop on the tour,
参观第一站
your new office.
你的新办公室
Oh, my.
天啊
You know, if I'm being honest, Sandy,
说实话 桑迪先生
there was a minute there where I didn't think I was gonna make it.
有那么一刻 我还以为自己失败了
Lockjaw, we're lucky to have you.
勒喉乔 有你加入是我们的幸事
Now, obviously, goes without saying,
好了 如你所见 大家都不在
this is just one place where you can hang your hat,
这个办公室只是给你挂挂帽子
take meetings, stow a few personal items.
开开会 放放个人物品的地方
We like our members to feel they have a home away from home,
我们希望每个成员都在总部有个家
any time, day or night.
随时都可以回来
That's a fine idea.
这个理念太棒了
Now, it's empty right now,
办公室现在还空着
But we'll let you personalize it.
但你可以自己布置
A man's taste defines him, doesn't it?
一个人的品味是最重要的
It does indeed, sir.
您说得太对了
And here we are.
好的 我们到了
Suite 55.
第55套间
Look at that view.
看看这景色
Would you look at that?
真是太美了
May I?
我能进吗？
Absolutely.
当然可以
Damn it. I forgot your keys.
糟糕 忘了拿你的钥匙
Wait here, I'll just grab 'em from my office.
在这儿等着 我这就回办公室拿
Yes, sir.
遵命
I've been holding on to something for a while now
有一样东西 在我这儿保管很久了
and I wanted to give it to you.
现在我想把它给你
Okay?
好吗？
And I didn't give it to you before because I...
之前没有给你是因为...
I just didn't wanna expose you to certain stuff.
我不想让你过早地接触这些事情
You know, I didn't want you to feel...
说实话我不想让你...
sad...
伤心
or confused about it.
或者为这些事烦恼
I don't know. I don't know what I wanted.
我不知道我想要什么
I wanted...
我只是
I wanted to protect you.
我想要保护你
From all your mom's shit.
不要受你妈妈的影响
From all my shit.
也别受我影响
I just, I suppose I wanted to be the one
我大概只是想 当个好爸爸
that you came to for help, right?
这样 你有困难的时候会来找我帮忙
You know, the one, the cool dad
当一个很酷的爸爸
that you could say anything to.
能让你敞开心扉
Even though I know that's impossible.
虽然我知道这是不可能的
【火化：违背传统福音派的葬制 历史上用作对异己的净化与消灭】
But I don't want...
但我不想
I don't wanna lie to you about anything anymore.
我不想对你撒谎 以后再也不会了
【毒气室与焚化：对应纳粹时期的制度化灭绝 暗示对他者的系统性权利剥夺】
And I've been holdin' on to somethin' for a couple years now
我保管它已经好多年了
and I just wanna...
不过现在
I just wanna give it to you.
我想把它交给你
Okay, I'm gonna share this with you
好吧 我这就拿出来
and if you wanna see it,
那个 要是你想看
You can see it.
你就看
Do you wanna see it?
你要看吗？
I don't know what it is, Dad.
我都不知道那是什么 爸爸
You don't know what it is?
你猜不到是什么？
No.
猜不到
It's a letter.
这是 一封信
It's a letter from your mom.
是你妈妈写来的信
Is it for me or for you?
是给我的 还是给你的？
It's for you.
是给你的
You wanna go read it alone?
你想一个人看对吗？
Go ahead.
去吧
Dear Charlene...
“亲爱的夏琳
Hello from the other side of the shadows.
“我从远影里向你问好”
I don't mean to shock you,
“我不想吓到你
but I've been contemplatin' writin' you for a long time.
“但我真的一直想要给你写信”
I often wake up and I find it completely crazy how
“有时醒来 感觉很不真实
and why I am where
“我怎么会
I am today.
“会变成今天这样？”
And disconnected from my family.
“和家人都断了联系”
I pretended my whole life.
“我的一生都在假装
I pretended to be strong...
“假装坚强
pretended to be dead.
“假装已死”
Is it too late for us, after all my lies?
“我说了那么多谎话 还能面对你吗？”
Are you happy?
“你过得开心吗？
Do you have love?
“有没有爱的人？”
What will you do when you get older?
“等你长大了想要做什么？”
Will you try to change the world, like I did?
“你会像我一样想改变世界吗？”
We failed.
“我们失败了
But maybe you will not.
“但也许你不会
Maybe you will be the one who puts the world right.
“也许你能让世界变得更好”
I think of you every single day...
“我每天都在想你
every single day.
“每天”
And I wish I had been strong for the both of us.
“真希望那时我能为我们母女撑起一片新天地”
I know someday...
“我知道有一天
when it's right and it's safe...
“等时机合适 安全的时候
you will find me.
“你会找到我”
Please send a kiss to your dad...
“替我吻一下你爸爸
my Ghetto Pat.
“我的穷鬼帕特”
Love, your mom,
“爱你的妈妈
Perfidia.
“叛娅”
How do I get this flash to work?
帮我看看自拍闪光灯 应该怎么用的
It's not gettin' my face.
照不到我的脸
I don't know how to get it to get my face.
怎么才能让闪光灯照到我的脸？
Swipe up, and then there's a lightning bolt.
上面有一个闪电符号
And then on there,
点一下会出来
it says, "Flash auto on and off."
闪光灯 自动 打开 关闭
No.
不闪啊
Well, if you push the...
那么你就按一下...
There's a little...
哪儿有个...
There's a little circle on the bottom right side. Click that.
右下角应该有个按钮切换到自拍 你点一下
Okay. Or take it with the back.
或者用后置摄像头拍
I guess that's fine.
都可以
- QST, QST. - I gotta press the circle.
- “通告 重要通告” - 右下角按钮是吗？
This is N6EDG,
“这里是N6-EDG
the Whiskey Sour in Oakland.
“来自奥克兰的‘威士忌酸酒’”
QST signal from the Whiskey Sour in Oakland.
“‘威士忌酸酒’进行全台通告”
Did they say Oakland?
他是说奥克兰吗？
- MKU raids in progress. - Yeah.
- “人类联盟正在突袭” - 对
（瑟吉奥·圣卡洛斯忍者学院）
Repeat, MKU raids in progress.
“重复 人类联盟正在突袭”
Meeting point for protesters is Lincoln Park.
“抗议集合点在林肯公园”
QST, this is the Whiskey Sour.
“全台通告 这里是‘威士忌酸酒’”
All hands on deck.
“大家都快来
N6EDG.
“这里是N6-EDG”
You know, Oakland's a three-and-a-half-hour drive from here.
我说 开车去奥克兰 可要三个半小时呢
Yeah.
知道
You know that's far, right?
那可够远的
Well, it's raining out.
还下着雨呢
Hey!
嘿
Be careful.
小心点儿
I won't.
才不要
《一战再战》
♪ Well, she was an American girl ♪
♪ 她是一个美国女孩
编剧及导演
保罗·托马斯·安德森
♪ Raised on promises ♪
♪ 从小到大充满希望 ♪
制片人
亚当·索姆纳
♪ She couldn't help thinkin' that there ♪
♪ 她忍不住想
♪ Was a little more to life ♪
♪ 在别的地方
制片人
萨拉·墨菲
保罗·托马斯·安德森
♪ Somewhere else ♪
♪ 还有更精彩人生 ♪
主演
莱昂纳多·迪卡普里奥 饰 父亲鲍勃
♪ After all It was a great big world ♪
♪ 毕竟 这世界多么广阔
主演
西恩·潘 饰 上校勒喉乔
♪ With lots of places to run to ♪
♪ 有太多地方值得一去
主演
本尼西奥·德尔·托罗 饰 柔道大师圣卡洛斯
♪ Yeah, and if she had to die tryin' ♪
♪ 如果她一生只能止于尝试
主演
雷吉娜·赫尔 饰 接应人迪安德拉
♪ She had one little promise ♪
♪ 那她心中还有个
♪ She was gonna keep ♪
♪ 小小的希望 ♪
主演
缇雅娜·泰勒 饰 母亲叛娅
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ 噢耶 ♪
主演
蔡斯·英菲尼迪 饰 女儿薇拉
♪ All right ♪
♪ 没错 ♪
♪ Take it easy, baby ♪
♪ 慢一点儿 宝贝 ♪
制作公司
古拉迪影业
♪ Make it last all night ♪
♪ 持续一整夜 ♪
♪ She was an American girl ♪
♪ 她是一个美国女孩 ♪
出品公司
华纳兄弟影业
联合出品
领域娱乐
摄影
迈克尔·鲍曼
♪ Well, it was kind of cold that night ♪
♪ 那一晚有些寒冷
艺术指导
弗洛伦西亚·马丁
♪ She stood alone on her balcony ♪
♪ 她独自站在阳台上 ♪
剪辑
安迪·贾尔根森
♪ Yeah, she could hear the cars roll by ♪
♪ 耳边传来阵阵车声
配乐
强尼·格林伍德
♪ Out on four forty-one ♪
♪ 441号公路车流不息
字幕译制
上海电影译制厂
蒙太奇字幕组
♪ Like waves crashin' on the beach ♪
♪ 就像浪潮拍打着海岸 ♪
翻译
上海电影译制厂: 许诺 & 徐子怡
蒙太奇字幕组 : 小p & 十三
♪ And for one desperate moment there ♪
♪ 在那绝望的时刻
蒙太奇字幕组
双语合并：novaeye & 小p & NickCollect & Lei
时间轴：小p & novaeye
校对：小p & 十三 & novaeye & NickCollect
♪ He crept back in her memory ♪
♪ 她逃回了记忆之中 ♪
蒙太奇字幕组
注释：小p & 十三
后期特效：NickCollect
♪ God, it's so painful ♪
♪ 这一切多么悲伤
蒙太奇字幕组
Telegram和IRC交流群：MontageSubs
♪ Something that's so close ♪
♪ 明明近在咫尺
蒙太奇字幕组字幕许可
原创部分许可CC BY‑NC‑SA 4.0
♪ And still so far out of reach ♪
♪ 却触不可及 ♪
影片灵感源于托马斯·品钦所著小说
《葡萄园》
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ 噢耶 ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ 没错 ♪
♪ Take it easy, baby ♪
♪ 慢一点儿 宝贝 ♪
♪ Make it last all night ♪
♪ 持续一整夜 ♪
♪ She was an American girl ♪
♪ 她是一个美国女孩 ♪
♪ You will not be able to stay home, brother ♪
♪ 你没法在家坐视不管 哥们儿 ♪
♪ You will not be able to plug in turn on and cop out ♪
♪ 你没法打开电视逃避现实 ♪
♪ You will not be able to lose yourself on skag ♪
♪ 你没法用药物来麻痹掩目 ♪
♪ And skip out for beer during commercials because ♪
♪ 你没法在广告时间出门买啤酒 因为
♪ The revolution will not be televised ♪
♪ 革命永远不会被喉舌转播 ♪
♪ There will be no pictures of pigs shooting down brothers on the instant replay ♪
♪ 他们实施的暴力 永远不会播出 ♪
♪ There will be no pictures of Whitney Young ♪
♪ 要是惠特尼·杨被示众
【惠特尼·杨：黑人民权领袖 此处指当局常以“平息骚乱”名义隐去真实画面】
♪ Being run out of harlem on a rail with a brand new process ♪
♪ 电视上绝对没有这场面 ♪
♪ There will be no slow motion or still lifes of Roy Wilkins ♪
♪ 你也看不到罗伊·威尔金斯
【罗伊·威尔金斯：黑人民权领袖 美国有色人种协进会前任领导人】
♪ Strolling through Watts in a red, black and green liberation jumpsuit ♪
♪ 穿着红黑绿的解放服
【红黑绿解放色：泛非主义旗色 红为血与抗争 黑为非裔身份 绿为非洲土地】
♪ That he has been saving for just the proper occasion ♪
♪ 在镜头前亮相 ♪
【看不到在镜头前亮相：批判媒体美化消费黑人解放并隐去其政治实质】
♪ Green Acres, Beverly Hillbillies and Hooterville Junction ♪
♪ 新青入乡 暴富新贵 中枢小镇 ♪
♪ Will no longer be so damn relevant ♪
♪ 上层建筑再也不重要了 ♪
♪ And women will not care if Dick finally got down with Jane ♪
♪ 洗脑的肥皂剧
♪ On Search for tomorrow ♪
♪ 也洗不掉她们的关切 ♪
♪ Because Black people will be in the street ♪
♪ 因为黑人会走上街头 ♪
♪ Looking for a brighter day ♪
♪ 带着未来的希冀 ♪
♪ The revolution will not be televised ♪
♪ 革命永远不会被喉舌转播 ♪
♪ Will not be televised ♪
♪ 不会被喉舌转播 ♪
♪ The revolution will be no re-run, brothers ♪
♪ 革命永远不会有重播 ♪
♪ The revolution will be live ♪
♪ 革命只能在现场看得到 ♪
♪ God rest ye merry gentlemen ♪
♪ 愿你们得到欢乐
♪ Let nothing you dismay ♪
♪ 愿你们不要沮丧 ♪
♪ Remember Christ our savior ♪
♪ 请记住那位圣人
♪ Was born on Christmas day ♪
♪ 就在圣诞节降生 ♪
♪ To save us all from Satan's power ♪
♪ 他救我们远离魔鬼
♪ When we were gone astray ♪
♪ 使我们不致迷途 ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy comfort and joy ♪
♪ 平安和欢乐的消息 一路传来 ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy ♪
♪ From God our heavenly father ♪
♪ 从那遥远的天上
♪ A blessed angel came ♪
♪ 来了一位天使 ♪
♪ And unto certain shepherds ♪
♪ 他为某个牧羊人
♪ Brought tidings of the same ♪
♪ 带来了好消息 ♪
♪ How bad in Bethlehem was born ♪
♪ 在伯利恒
♪ The son of God by name ♪
♪ 有一位圣人出生了 ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy comfort and joy ♪
♪ 平安和欢乐的消息 一路传来 ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy ♪
♪ Now to the Lord sing praises ♪
♪ 在场的人
♪ All you within this place ♪
♪ 都高声歌颂 ♪
♪ And with true love and brotherhood ♪
♪ 团结友爱
♪ Each other now embrace ♪
♪ 拥抱彼此 ♪
♪ This holy tide of Christmas ♪
♪ 圣诞的气氛
♪ All others doth deface ♪
♪ 消除了不和 ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy comfort and joy ♪
♪ 平安和欢乐的消息 一路传来 ♪
♪ Oh tidings of comfort and joy ♪
I can do it now.
我能接着拍
Thank you.
谢谢
- Colin, are you good? - Yeah.
- 科林 准备好了吗？ - 好了
And roll sound, roll, roll, please.
场录 开始录音 开始
（谨以此片献给亚当）
【亚当·索姆纳：于2024年11月去世 曾多次担任导演安德森的副导演】
Hey, quiet please. Here we go, shooting.
都请安静 开拍了
That's how we're rolling
电影就是这样拍的
（领域娱乐）
Action.
开拍
（华纳兄弟影业）
蒙太奇字幕组 (MontageSubs)
用爱发电 ♥ Powered by love